¬ Generated by localisation spreadsheet
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_INCOME}Settlement Income
{TMT_LOYALTY_TOOLTIP_REVOLTING}Loyalty: Potential for revolt
{TMT_LOYALTY_TOOLTIP_RIOTING}Loyalty: Potential for riots
{TMT_LOYALTY_TOOLTIP_DISILLUSIONED}Loyalty: Disillusioned
{TMT_LOYALTY_TOOLTIP_CONTENT}Loyalty: Content
{TMT_LOYALTY_TOOLTIP_HAPPY}Loyalty: Happy
{TMT_GROWTH_TOOLTIP_GROWTH}Population: Increasing
{TMT_GROWTH_TOOLTIP_STATIC}Population: No Growth
{TMT_GROWTH_TOOLTIP_DECLINING}Population: Decreasing
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_STATUS_TRAINING}Currently training units
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_STATUS_BUILDING}Currently constructing buildings
{TMT_LCLICK_FOR_BUILD_OPTIONS}Left-click to see upgrade options for this building
{TMT_CONSTRUCTION_HELP}Left-click to add to queue
{TMT_CONSTRUCTION_REMOVE_HELP}Left-click to remove from queue
{TMT_COST_OF_CONSTRUCTION}Cost to construct item
{TMT_TIME_TO_CONSTRUCT}Number of turns required to construct item
{TMT_COST_OF_RECRUITMENT_UNIT}Cost to recruit unit
{TMT_TIME_TO_RECRUIT}Number of turns required to train
{TMT_SEASON_SUMMER}Summer
{TMT_SEASON_WINTER}Winter
{TMT_REMAINING_ACTION_POINTS}Movement points\nThe dark blue bar represents points remaining\nLight blue section represents affect\non movement points after current\naction is performed
{TMT_ACCEPT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION}Build selected item
{TMT_CANCEL_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION}Do not build anything
{TMT_BUILD_FORT_OR_WATCHTOWER}Construct fort or watchtower
{TMT_CANNOT_BUILD_FORT_OR_WATCHTOWER}Cannot construct fort or watchtower here
{TMT_CANNOT_ATTACK_FROM_SIEGED_SETTLEMENT}When under siege it is only possible to attack the sieging army
{TMT_SHOW_GENERAL_UNIT_DETAILS}Show unit details for this character's bodyguard unit
{TMT_LCLICK_SELECT}Left-click to select
{TMT_RCLICK_INFO}Right-click to get further information
{TMT_LDBL_CLICK_INFO}Double Left-click to get further information
{TMT_CURSOR_ATTACK}Right-click to attack
{TMT_CURSOR_MOVE}Right-click to move to position
{TMT_CURSOR_SELECT}Right-click to select
{TMT_CURSOR_MOVE_MAP}Scroll map
{TMT_CURSOR_MOUSE_LOOK}Mouse look
{TMT_CURSOR_CLICK_DOWN}Click down
{TMT_CURSOR_EXCHANGE}Right-click to exchange units and characters 
{TMT_CURSOR_DEFAULT_ACTION}Right-click to perform mission
{TMT_CURSOR_NO_ACTION}No action possible on this target
{TMT_CURSOR_ENTER_SETTLEMENT}Right-click to enter settlement
{TMT_CURSOR_DISEMBARK}Right-click to disembark
{TMT_CURSOR_SET_RALLY_POINT}Right-click to set settlement's rally point
{TMT_CURSOR_AUTO_MERGE}Right-click to merge units 
{TMT_NO_MULTITURN_MISSIONS}Cannot attack or perform missions over multiple turns
{TMT_NO_MULTITURN_EXCHANGES}Cannot merge or exchange units over multiple turns
{TMT_SIEGE_EQUIPMENT_NOT_REQUIRED}Construction of this siege equipment is not required
{TMT_NO_DIPLOMACY_WITH_REBELS}Diplomacy is not possible with rebels
{TMT_SILVER_TOOLTIP}Silver Mines can be constructed at the nearby settlement
{TMT_GOLD_TOOLTIP}Gold Mines can be constructed at the nearby settlement
{TMT_IRON_TOOLTIP}Iron - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_GRAIN_TOOLTIP}Grain - a valuable resource\nIncreases population growth in local settlement
{TMT_IVORY_TOOLTIP}A gate to Oblivion might spawn here. Once it does, put your character at the gate to use it.
{TMT_WINE_TOOLTIP}Wine - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_SLAVES_TOOLTIP}Slaves - a valuable resource
{TMT_CHOCOLATE_TOOLTIP}Netch Skin - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_FISH_TOOLTIP}Fish - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_TIMBER_TOOLTIP}Timber - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_MARBLE_TOOLTIP}Malachite Mines can be constructed at the nearby settlement
{TMT_TEXTILES_TOOLTIP}Textiles - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_DYES_TOOLTIP}Dyes - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_TOBACCO_TOOLTIP}THE DIRENNI TOWER: Adamantine Tower - The Direnni Tower, also known as the Adamantine Tower, Ada-Mantia, or Ur-Tower, is believed to be the oldest building in Tamriel, if not the entirety of Nirn. It is believed to have been built by the Aedra soon after the creation of Mundus, around ME 2500. The structure became known as Direnni Tower in honor of the Direnni Clan, and is located on the Isle of Balfiera. Here the Aedra made their Convention - an event that ended the Dawn Era and signaled the start of the Merethic Era. This occurred when Akatosh created the Adamantine Tower in order to convene with the Aedra and decide the punishment for Lorkhan, who tricked them into creating Mundus. The Aedra punished Lorkhan by removing his heart, however the heart was tied to the existence of Nirn. Auri-El and Trinimac, after a failed attempt to destroy the heart, tied it to an arrow and shot it into the sea in east. Where the heart landed formed the Red Mountain, and the island of Vvardenfell rose around the volcano. Sometime after the events at the beginning of the Merethic Era, the Direnni Clan decided to use the tower located in the Isle of Balfiera. Many Dirennis were famous, and the clan has lived in this tower for many centuries. Later, it was renamed as the Direnni Tower, in honor of the clan. Some time prior to 3E 405, Lysandus's mother, Nulfaga, put a curse on Direnni Tower to trap Medora Direnni. After being cured by the Hero of Daggerfall in 3E 405, the hero saved Medora and restored the Direnni Tower to its original state.
{TMT_SILK_TOOLTIP}Silk - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_SUGAR_TOOLTIP}Moon Sugar - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_SULFUR_TOOLTIP}Sulphur - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_FURS_TOOLTIP}Furs - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_TIN_TOOLTIP}Tin - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_SPICES_TOOLTIP}Spices - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_COTTON_TOOLTIP}THE CRYSTAL TOWER: The Crystal Tower, also known as the Crystal-Like-Law or Lawful Crystal, a mystical structure located on the Summerset Isles, which, before the construction of the Arcane University, was the supposed pinnacle of magical learning in Tamriel. Crystal Tower, a monument to the spirit of the elven people and one of their greatest engineering projects. Within the glittering walls of the Tower are housed the graves of the early Aldmeri settlers, preserved forever as a lasting symbol of the power of the people for that brief moment in history, fully unified. Also known as Crystal-Like-Law, this structure is of symbolic importance to the Altmer just as White-Gold Tower was for the Ayleids. The tower was constructed by the ancient Aldmer, and was considered sacred to the Altmer. Up until the construction of the Arcane University in the Second Era, the tower was the center of magical learning in Tamriel. It is also known for the fact that it contained one of the pieces of the Staff of Chaos.
{TMT_AMBER_TOOLTIP}Ebony Mines can be constructed at the nearby settlement
{TMT_COAL_TOOLTIP}Chitin - a valuable trade resource
{TMT_WOOL_TOOLTIP}FANG LAIR: Fang Lair or "Arkngthamz-Phng" is a dwemer stronghold located along the Dragon's Teeth Mountains in the province of Hammerfell. Fang Lair was constructed as a Dwemer Mine in the Dragon's Teeth, but it was abandoned.\n The Dwemers of the Rourken Clan had yearned to leave from the province of Morrowind, desiring to build beyond the province. It is because of the Rourken Clan; there are various Dwemer Cities throughout Hammerfell and the Abecean Sea. Rourken Clan had created a trail which caused the Dwemers of Kragen to follow the Rourken Dwemer to the western desert and built their settlements, with Arkngthamz-Phng being one of them. Before this city was built in the Dragon's Teeth, the Kragen Clan had created the Dwemer city-state of Arkngthamz, located in the Reach of Skyrim. Arkngthamz inspired more Dwemer clans in Morrowind to expand to the west, in Skyrim and Hammerfell. Arkngthamz was built for mining Aetherium, a powerful mineral with magicka properties. Because of this, Arkngthamz allied with other Dwemer city-states (i.e. Mzulft and Irkngthand). Eventually, the Kragen Clan moved into Hammerfell, in the Dragon's Teeth Mountains, where they established Arkngthamz-Phng. The city-state of Arkngthamz-Phng would prosper amidst the Dragon's Teeth.\n On one fateful day, the Dragon known as Thurvokun had fled the province of Skyrim several years prior, and eventually found Arkngthamz-Phng. With his immense power, Thurvokun had driven the Kragen Clan out of Arkngthamz-Phng, claiming the ancient Dwemer city as his nest. Because of living in the city, the ruins were renamed into Fang Lair, known for being a Dragon Lair. Before living in Fang Lair, Thurvokun was prominent during the Dragon War. Instead of choosing a side, he remained neutral and fled his Dragon Cult. Because he was not given an eternal soul, he was slowly dying of age. In the late first era, an Altmeri warrior named Caluurion had traveled to Fang Lair with his three companions, Ulfnor and Sabina Cedus, to subdue the beast. It was at this point, Emperor Reman Cyrodiil had already called an end to hunting Dragons. In the end, both Thurvokun and the three companions were killed, with their remains staying in Fang Lair, untempered for years.\n It is also known for the fact that it contained one of the pieces of the Staff of Chaos.
{TMT_DOGS_TOOLTIP}HIGH HROTHGAR: High Hrothgar is a monastery that sits at the top of the Seven Thousand Steps to the Throat of the World — the highest point in Tamriel. It is here the ancient Greybeards reside, living in absolute silence to better attune themselves to the voice of the sky.\n\nThe act of climbing the Seven Thousand Steps holds a spiritual significance for many Nords due to the belief that Men were created by Kyne on this mountain when the sky breathed onto the land. This belief has led to pilgrims from all across Tamriel traveling to the Throat of the World, and several may be encountered along the mountain path either meditating or studying the etched tablets.
{TMT_CAMELS_TOOLTIP}THE HALLS OF COLOSSUS: The Halls of Colossus - an ancient structure, erected, presumably in the Second Era. Local tribes of khajiits argue that this coliseum was erected by some mythical "giants", but there is no evidence that Elsweyr's territory has ever been inhabited by creatures like giants. On the contrary, there is a point of view that the Halls were built under the direction of Zurin Arctus at the end of the Second Era, by the order of Emperor Tiber Septim. This assumption is based on the fact that it was within the walls of this monumental coliseum the ancient Dwemer colossus, Numidium, was kept and built, and later used by Tiber to defeat the Aldmeri Dominion. From here the structure could get its name - "Halls of the Colossus". However, its true origin remains a mystery. It is also known for the fact that it contained one of the pieces of the Staff of Chaos.
{TMT_ELEPHANTS_TOOLTIP}Silt Striders, fearsome beasts
{TMT_ROADS_TOOLTIP}Road: Allows armies to march further\nAlso adds to trade income\nThe amount of traffic indicates the amount of trade
{TMT_PAVED_ROADS_TOOLTIP}Paved road: Allows armies to march efficiently at speed\nAlso adds to trade income\nThe amount of traffic indicates the amount of trade
{TMT_HIGHWAYS_TOOLTIP}Highways: Allows armies to march long distances\nAlso adds to trade income\nThe amount of traffic indicates the amount of trade
{TMT_SEA_LANES_TOOLTIP}Trade route between settlements with ports
{TMT_FAMOUS_BATTLE_SITE_TOOLTIP}An epic battle of great renown was fought here
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_0}A ripe turnip has more influence over the ways of men than this lowly wretch
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_1}Even when he is full of conviction, nobody listens too much to this man
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_2}It is said even this man's wife barely takes heed of what he says
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_3}Though his statements are usually considered sound, he lacks the charisma to influence others
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_4}This man is considered decent counsel, but is yet to hold any real presence in the royal courts
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_5}Considered important enough that most minor lordlings would listen carefully to his counsel
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_6}Though he may not always win every debate he enters, his counsel always wins him respect
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_7}Is known to be able to make others adopt a perspective that is otherwise against their beliefs
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_8}Considered an even-handed font of wisdom on most matters, even by the enemies of his people
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_9}So convincing are this man's arguments that he can manipulate a learned audience with ease
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_10}Scholars follow this man, seeking to quote his highly influential statements and musings
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_0}This man would wet himself at the notion he should be in charge at all
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_1}Young peasant girls laugh when this man tries to tell them what to do
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_2 }A born follower, this man has no notion of what leadership is about
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_3 }Understands the concepts of chain of command, but knows little of what orders to give
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_4 }Hardly a tactical genius, but this man is showing some aptitude for leadership
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_5 }Given the right troops and conditions, this man can typically lead an armed force to victory
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_6 }Calm and confident at the head of an army, and usually decisive in victory
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_7 }Though he is but one man, his aura of command is powerful enough to inspire many on the battlefield. 
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_8 }This man has leadership qualities to enable men to go beyond their own abilities on any battlefield. 
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_9 }So bold and confident in command, this man could lead an angry mob to conquer an empire
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_10}On the battlefield, this man's will is always realised! He is a true master of warfare
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_0}So naive and innocent is this one, he lacks the cunning to sneak up on even a corpse
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_1}Clumsy and conspicuous, only a fool would rely on this man for acts of espionage
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_2}He may be willing to do the dubious, but he lacks the guile and cunning to do it well
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_3}More cunning than most of the night watch... But not all of them
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_4}Usually capable of pulling off minor acts of espionage given the proper preparation
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_5}Discreet and delicate enough to be entrusted with dangerous clandestine tasks
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_6}Has proven more than capable of committing cunning clandestine acts
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_7}Foxes and weasels have nothing on this man in terms of raw cunning
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_8}Not even a bloodhound could track this man's movements, he is but a shadow
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_9}This man is the embodiment of subtlety, secrecy and stealth
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_10}Like the shadows themselves, this man is everywhere at once without being tangible anywhere. 
{TMT_TOGGLE_AUTOMANAGEMENT}Toggle auto-management of this settlement
{TMT_DECREASE_TAXATION}Decrease taxation
{TMT_INCREASE_TAXATION}Increase taxation
{TMT_CHANGE_GOVERNOR_POLICY}Change governor policy
{TMT_DECREASE_GAMES_FREQUENCY}Decrease frequency of games and/or races
{TMT_INCREASE_GAMES_FREQUENCY}Increase frequency of games and/or races
{TMT_CURRENTLY_SELECTED_CHARACTER}Character currently selected:
{TMT_CURRENTLY_SELECTED_SETTLEMENT}Settlement currently selected:
{TMT_CURRENTLY_SELECTED_FORT}Fort currently selected
{TMT_CURRENTLY_SELECTED_RALLY_POINT}Rally point currently selected
{TMT_CURRENTLY_SELECTED_RALLY_POINTS}Rally points currently selected
{TMT_LCLICK_ZOOM_TO_POS}Left-click to locate item on map
{TMT_SHOW_SELECTED_ITEM}This area shows the currently selected item
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_NO_GENERAL}Armies without generals cannot construct forts or watchtowers
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_NOT_NAMED_CHARACTER}Only generals can commission forts and watchtowers
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_IN_SEA_REGION}Cannot build a fort or watchtower in the sea
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_FORT_IN_ENEMY_TERRITORY}Cannot build a fort in enemy territory
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_FORT_INVALID_GAME_TILE}This is an invalid position for a fort
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_FORT_NOT_ENOUGH_MONEY}You do not have enough money to build a fort
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_WATCHTOWER_IN_ENEMY_TERRITORY}Cannot build a watchtower in enemy territory
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_WATCHTOWER_INVALID_GAME_TILE}This is an invalid position for a watchtower
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_WATCHTOWER_NOT_ENOUGH_MONEY}You do not have enough money to build a watchtower
{TMT_NOT_ENOUGH_MONEY_FOR_FORT_OR_WATCHTOWER}You do not have enough money to build a fort or watchtower
{TMT_CANNOT_RECRUIT_UNITS_IN_BATTLE}You cannot recruit units or mercenaries once a battle has been instigated
{TMT_NO_BODYGUARD_UNIT_TO_VIEW}There is no bodyguard unit to view for this character
{TMT_NOT_ENOUGH_INFO_FOR_BODYGUARD}Not enough information gathered about this character to view his bodyguard unit
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_STATUS_AUTOMANAGED}This settlement is auto-managed
{TMT_PIGS_TOOLTIP}Pigs: Allows the training of incendiary pig units
{TMT_CANNOT_ATTACK_SIEGED_SETTLEMENT}Cannot lay siege to a settlement that is besieged by a non allied faction
{TMT_CANNOT_CONSTRUCT_WHILST_SIEGING}Cannot build forts or watchtowers whilst laying siege
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_WATCHTOWER_SIEGING}Cannot build a watchtower whilst laying siege
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_FORT_SIEGING}Cannot build a fort whilst laying siege
{TMT_NEGATIVE_COMMAND}This man actually manages to hinder any chance his subordinates have of achieving military success.
{TMT_NEGATIVE_INFLUENCE}When this man states an opinion, everyone knows that the opposite must be true.
{TMT_NEGATIVE_MANAGEMENT}This man can bring chaos out of order. He needs a 'to do' list when visiting a latrine, yet still manages to go horribly wrong!
{TMT_NEGATIVE_SUBTERFUGE}This man's bumbling naivety helps everyone he deals with become a master of cunning and subterfuge. 
{TMT_SLAVES_TOOLTIP_SINGLE}Slaves - a valuable resource\nDistributed across all settlements with governors. Resource is exhausted after 1 more turn
{TMT_SHOW_GENERAL_UNIT_DETAILS_ARMY}Show details of the bodyguard unit for this army's general
{TMT_LCLICK_INFO}Left-click to get further information
{TMT_CANNOT_MERGE_AGENT}The selected character cannot be received at this location
{TMT_CANNOT_MERGE_AGENTS}The selected characters cannot be received at this location
{TMT_AUTO_MERGE_AGENTS}Right-click to automatically merge agents
{TMT_GOLD_MINE_TOOLTIP}Gold Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_SILVER_MINE_TOOLTIP}Silver Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_IRON_MINE_TOOLTIP}Iron Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_MARBLE_MINE_TOOLTIP}Malachite Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_SULFUR_MINE_TOOLTIP}Sulphur Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_TIN_MINE_TOOLTIP}Tin Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_AMBER_MINE_TOOLTIP}Ebony Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_COAL_MINE_TOOLTIP}Coal Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_NO_WITHDRAW_NAVY}Cannot withdraw: Navies cannot withdraw from battles
{TMT_NO_WITHDRAW_AMBUSH}Cannot withdraw: You have been successfully ambushed
{TMT_NO_WITHDRAW_SIEGE}Cannot withdraw: Your are under siege
{TMT_NO_WITHDRAW_AP}Cannot withdraw: No movement points remaining
{TMT_NO_WITHDRAW_RETREAT}Cannot withdraw: Nowhere to withdraw to
{TMT_ALREADY_CAPITAL}This settlement is already the capital
{TMT_NO_GENERAL_UNIT_TO_SHOW}No personal bodyguard unit to show
{TMT_DOCK_BLOCKADED}This dock is currently blockaded
{TMT_PORT_BLOCKADED}This port is currently blockaded
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_AUTOMANAGED_BUILDING}Cannot add this building as construction is being auto-managed
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_AUTOMANAGED_TRAINING}Cannot add this unit as recruitment is being auto-managed
{TMT_CANNOT_RECRUIT_MERCS_IN_BATTLE}Cannot recruit mercenaries once a battle has been instigated
{TMT_CANNOT_CHANGE_TAX_LEVEL_AS_AUTOMANAGED}Cannot change the tax level of this settlement as the faction's taxes are being auto-managed. Go to the faction summary scroll to change this
{TMT_CANNOT_CHANGE_CASTLE_TAX_LEVEL}Cannot change the tax level of the castle.
{TMT_CANNOT_DESTROY_THIS_BUILDING}This building cannot be destroyed
{TMT_RECOUP_AMOUNT}%d florins will be recouped.
{TMT_CANNOT_LEAVE_ZOC}Cannot move through an enemy's zone of control
{TMT_CAN_ONLY_SALLY_OUT_ONCE_PER_TURN}Can only sally out once per turn
{TMT_CANNOT_FLEE}This army cannot flee from the battle. If it loses, all units will be destroyed
{TMT_LOYALTY_TITLE}Loyalty
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_0}It is doubtful if this man has any loyalties at all, even unto himself
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_1}This man perceives loyalty as a trait of the weak and foolish
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_2}He may proclaim his loyalty as expected, though it is quite obviously just for appearances
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_3}Fallible like any other man, at least this one tries to be a good servant
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_4}Understands that acting obediently is sometimes more important than doing what would seem sensible
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_5}Loyal enough to obey an order that he does not see the sense behind without complaint
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_6}This man would only disobey an order if he truly believed that he would be commended for it afterwards
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_7}Even upon threat of death, this man is willing to endure great hardships in service of his master and people
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_8}Unquestioningly loyal, this man is an asset that his people can always depend upon 
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_9}When this man's master commands him, he knows that it will be done, or he shall die trying
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_10}This man is spoken of far and wide as the epitome of selfless obedience, and is universally admired for it
{TMT_NEGATIVE_LOYALTY}This man actually revels in deceiving and betraying any whom he believes trust him
{TMT_HORDE_OCCUPY_SETTLEMENT_TOOLTIP}Take this settlement and the surrounding region as a new homeland for your people. Your hordes will disband.
{TMT_HORDE_SACK_SETTLEMENT_TOOLTIP}Steal everything you can from this settlement. Wreak havoc, and continue the search for a new homeland for your hordes.
{TMT_CANNOT_LEAD_NIGHT_BATTLE}The commanding officer in this battle cannot lead night attacks
{TMT_CANNOT_DISEMBARK_HERE}Cannot disembark here
{TMT_CANNOT_FLEE_HORDE_PLAYER}This army cannot flee from the battle. If it loses, the settlement will be lost and all your people will be forced to find another land to call home
{TMT_CANNOT_FLEE_HORDE_NON_PLAYER}This army cannot flee from the battle. If it loses, the settlement will be lost and this nations people will be forced to find another land to call home
{TMT_SIEGE_EQUIPMENT_NOT_POSSIBLE}Construction of this siege equipment is not possible
{TMT_MEET_ENEMY}Sally forth to meet the enemy outside settlement
{TMT_MEET_ENEMY_AUTORESOLVE}Automatically resolve the battle outside settlement
{TMT_REMAIN_GARRISON}Keep your garrison inside the settlement
{TMT_FLEE}Flee, abandoning the settlement to the enemy
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_0}There's little to separate this wretched creature from a bar wench
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_1}More of a spoiled brat than an example of nobility
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_2}Lacks the grace and charm of other ladies of the court
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_3}Delicate enough to win over a simpler sort of man easily enough
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_4}About as enthralling as one expects from a princess
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_5}One of the fairer ladies of the royal courts
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_6}Graceful and endearing enough to instil trust in others
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_7}Beautiful and capable, her majesty is a true asset to her people
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_8}Intoxicatingly charming enough to always get what she wants
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_9}So charming that most men would fight to see her will be done
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_10}Her majesty's grace and charm makes her a dangerous political weapon
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_0}This man may like money, but he is useless with it
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_1}Barely grasps the basics of the barter system
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_2}Boasts no more business acumen than a common market vendor
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_3}An aspiring trader, possessing more ambition than experience or ability
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_4}A competent yet uninventive warrior of the mercantile world
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_5}Boasts a sound knowledge of local and foreign markets
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_6}Knows how to use money to achieve goals that strength and honour cannot
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_7}Can lay siege to your enemies coffers with almost certain success
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_8}Silver-tongued enough to sell paintings to the blind
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_9}A master of making money multiply with little effort on a grand scale
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_10}An infamous fiscal power in his own right
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_0}A walking bastion of blasphemy
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_1}Shows no real sense of spirituality 
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_2}Far from devout, and often far from the altar at mass
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_3}Complies with divine mandate with little apparent joy
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_4}Has the occasional need to pray for his sins
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_5}Shows a healthy respect for his faith
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_6}Pious, proper and proud of it
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_7}Clearly one touched with religious fervour
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_8}He doesn't just walk in the light, it shines from him
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_9}Has embraced his faith to a point of fanaticism
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_10}Widely considered a living saint, even by his enemies
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_0}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_1}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_2}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_3}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_4}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_5}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_6}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_7}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_8}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_9}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_10}Dungeon Scale
{TMT_NEGATIVE_CHARM}So vile is this woman that the doomsayers consider her a bad omen
{TMT_NEGATIVE_FINANCE}It is questionable whether or not this man can count properly
{TMT_NEGATIVE_PIETY}This man stops just short of publicly denouncing religion as nonsense
{TMT_NEGATIVE_MAGIC}Her only power is to inspire gossip and rumours amongst nervous villagers
{TMT_RESOURCE_TRADE_VALUE}Trade resource worth %d florins per turn
{TMT_TRADER_TRADE_VALUE}Trading %S, generating %d florins per turn
{TMT_TRADER_TRADE_TYPE}Trading %S
{TMT_NUM_MARRIAGES}%d marriage alliances with this faction 
{TMT_NEGATIVE_CHIVALRY}DO NOT TRANSLATE: SHOULD NEVER DISPLAY - negative chivalry
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_0}Neither remarkably noble nor nefarious
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_1}A well meaning warrior, still prone to barbaric ways
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_2}This man favours good virtues, he simply hasn't mastered them
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_3}More noble than a mere mercenary, but hardly known as a defender of the faith
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_4}Despite a few discrepancies, this man has only honourable intentions
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_5}Manages to adhere to the codes of chivalry admirably
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_6}Genuinely chivalrous and honourable to both master and minion alike
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_7}A man who would rather die than dishonour himself, or his people
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_8}Will only do what is right and just, even upon pain of death
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_9}A true champion of honour and virtue, revered even by his enemies
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_10}Destined to be considered the patron saint of knights
{TMT_NEGATIVE_DREAD}DO NOT TRANSLATE: SHOULD NEVER DISPLAY - negative dread
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_0}Neither remarkably noble nor nefarious
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_1}More concerned with survival than fighting honourably
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_2}Known for adopting less than admirable tactics to achieve victory
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_3}Has a habit of unnerving seasoned opponents with his overly grizzly ways
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_4}Consciously works terror and blackmail into his strategies
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_5}Some say his troops follow him out of fear rather than loyalty or pride
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_6}Shamelessly takes pleasure in causing pain and suffering
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_7}Commonly tortures his subjects as a display of authority
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_8}A man so malevolent, he considers honour and virtue foolish weaknesses
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_9}A notorious champion of darkness capable of evils few others are
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_10}Even the dauntless must be forced to face such a man
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_0}Even his own servants think twice before completing their chores
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_1}This leader has a serious inability to inspire others to follow
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_2}He simply lacks the spine and presence expected of a ruler
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_3}Some of his subjects will see things his way, yet not the majority
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_4}Though he has his detractors, he is too well respected for them to work openly
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_5}There is a general acceptance that his majesty is a competent ruler
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_6}Carries himself strongly enough to inspire confidence in his court
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_7}A natural born leader, rarely challenged or questioned
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_8}Capable of making men willingly follow a cause to their demise
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_9}Leads in a manner so inspiring none would think to question him
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_10}His people consider his word nothing less than divine mandate
{TMT_NEGATIVE_AUTHORITY}Purely a figurehead, this man's people do not think of him as their leader
{TMT_JOIN_CRUSADE}Join the Crusade
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_NOT_CALLED}There is no Crusade in progress to join
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_CHARACTER_EXCOMMUNICATED}Excommunicated character cannot join the Crusade
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_TOO_LATE}It's too late to join the Crusade
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_CHARACTER_IN_RESIDENCE}Cannot join the Crusade whilst in a settlement or fort
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_CHARACTER_ON_FLEET}Cannot join the Crusade whilst at sea
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_CHARACTER_NOT_ARMY_COMMANDER}Only the army commander may join the Crusade
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_INSUFFICIENT_UNITS}This character has too few units to join the crusade
{TMT_ABANDON_CRUSADE}Abandon Crusade
{TMT_JOIN_JIHAD}Join the Jihad
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_NOT_CALLED}There is no Jihad in progress to join
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_TOO_LATE}It's too late to join the Jihad
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_CHARACTER_IN_RESIDENCE}Cannot join the Jihad whilst in a settlement or fort
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_CHARACTER_ON_FLEET}Cannot join the Jihad whilst at sea
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_CHARACTER_NOT_ARMY_COMMANDER}Only the commanding general may join the Jihad
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_INSUFFICIENT_UNITS}This character has too few units to join the Jihad
{TMT_ABANDON_JIHAD}Abandon Jihad
{TMT_CRUSADE_CANNOT_ATTACK_CATHOLIC}A Crusading army cannot attack a Catholic faction
{TMT_JIHAD_CANNOT_ATTACK_MUSLIM}An army on a Jihad cannot attack an Islamic faction
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE}Request the Pope to commission a Crusade
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_IN_PROGRESS}Crusade already in progress	
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_NOT_ENOUGH_PAPAL_FAVOUR}Not enough Papal favour points to request a Crusade
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_TOO_SOON}Too soon since last Crusade to request another
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_OK_NOT_SELECTED}Select a Crusade target from the list first
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_OK_NO_TARGETS}No valid Crusade targets available
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_OK}Request a Crusade to the selected target
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_CANCEL}Close this scroll without requesting a Crusade
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD}Declare a Jihad
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_IN_PROGRESS}Jihad already in progress
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_NOT_ENOUGH_RELIGION}This Imam lacks the Piety required to call a Jihad
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_TOO_SOON}Too soon since last Jihad to call another
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_OK_NOT_SELECTED}Select a Jihad target from the list first
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_OK_NO_TARGETS}No valid Jihad targets available
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_OK}Call a Jihad against the selected target
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_CANCEL}Close this scroll without starting a Jihad
{TMT_VOTE}Vote for this faction
{TMT_INITIATE_DIPLOMACY}Initiate diplomatic negotiations with this faction
{TMT_RESTRICTED_AREA}Restricted area 
{TMT_AVAILABLE_SUITORS}Potential suitors are in this army
{TMT_NO_AVAILABLE_SUITORS}No potential suitors in this army
{TMT_DIP_DEMEANOUR}A measure of how the other negotiator feels about you, and your proposals
{TMT_DIP_BALANCE}A measure of how generous or demanding your proposals are
{TMT_DIP_RELATIONS}A measure of how the other faction feels about yours
{TMT_DIP_REPUTATION}A measure of this faction's reliability
{TMT_DIP_POWER}A measure of this faction's military might
{TMT_DIP_WEALTH}A measure of this faction's current wealth
{TMT_DIP_PRIORITIES}Things this faction is believed to want from yours
{TMT_DIP_STANCES_NO_ALLIES}This faction has no allies
{TMT_DIP_STANCES_NO_ENEMIES}This faction is not at war with any other faction
{TMT_DIP_STANCES_ALLIES}Factions allied to this faction
{TMT_DIP_STANCES_ENEMIES}Factions at war with this faction
{TMT_DIP_STANCE_ALLIED}You are allied to this faction
{TMT_DIP_STANCE_NEUTRAL}You are neutral towards this faction
{TMT_DIP_STANCE_ENEMY}You are at war with this faction
{TMT_DIP_TRADE_RIGHTS_GRANTED}Number of turns trade rights have existed
{TMT_DIP_MILITARY_ACCESS_RECEIVED}Number of turns this faction has granted yours military access
{TMT_DIP_MILITARY_ACCESS_GIVEN}Number of turns you have granted this faction military access
{TMT_DIP_TRIBUTE_PAYED}Finances you are sending this faction each turn
{TMT_DIP_TRIBUTE_RECEIVED}Finances this faction is sending yours each turn
{TMT_DIP_ASSISTANCE_REQUESTED_AGAINST}The faction you have requested military assistance against
{TMT_DIP_ASSISTANCE_PROVIDED_AGAINST}The faction you have agreed to offer military assistance against
{TMT_DIP_PROTECTOR}The faction that this faction is offering you military assistance against
{TMT_NO_TREATIES}You have no diplomatic agreements at all with this faction
{TMT_RANSOM_BUTTON}Offer to ransom back the enemy troops
{TMT_RELEASE_BUTTON}Release the enemy troops
{TMT_EXECUTE_BUTTON}Execute the enemy troops or use Necromancy to raise them as undead (requires Necromancy trait). To be able to raise the dead, you have to left click on your Necromancer first thing after the battle, and raise the dead using the mercenary pool. If you click on something else, you will no longer be able to use necromancy, and they will be just executed.
{TMT_ACCEPT_RANSOM_BUTTON}Agree to pay the ransom for your captured troops
{TMT_CANNOT_ACCEPT_RANSOM}Unfortunately, your coffers lack the funds required to pay the ransom
{TMT_REJECT_RANSOM_BUTTON}Decline to pay the ransom for your captured troops
{TMT_LCLICK_ZOOM_TO_CHARACTER}Left-click to locate character
{TMT_TIME_TO_NEXT_UNIT}Turns to next available unit: %d


{TMT_BUILD_WATCHTOWER}Construct watchtower
{TMT_CANNOT_BUILD_WATCHTOWER}Cannot construct watchtower here
{TMT_NOT_ENOUGH_MONEY_FOR_WATCHTOWER}You do not have enough money to build a watchtower
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_NOT_NAMED_CHARACTER_WATCHTOWER}Only generals can commission watchtowers

{TMT_HOTSEAT_MESSAGE}Click to send a hotseat message
{TMT_HS_CLEAR_BUTTON}Clear the current message
{TMT_HS_CANCEL_BUTTON}Cancel message to this player
{TMT_HS_SEND_BUTTON}Send message to this player
