¬ Localised file for campaign descriptions
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TITLE}War of the Ring
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_TITLE}Anduin
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_DESCR}Leader: Huntmaster Beorn\nHeir: Grimbeorn\nCapital: Beorn's Hall\n\n\n\n"[Home] of many sturdy men, and to their land between the Mountains and Mirkwood neither orc nor wolf dared to go. "Indeed," said Glóin, "if it were not for the Beornings, the passage from Dale to Rivendell would long ago have become impossible. They are valiant men and keep open the High Pass and the Ford of Carrock. But their tolls are high," he added with a shake of his head; "and like Beorn of old they are not over fond of dwarves. Still, they are trusty, and that is much in these days." - Account of the Valesmen\n\nStarting Location:\nStarting with quite a few provinces and surrounded by natural defences on all sides including: The Misty Mountains; The Grey Mountains and; the Forest of Mirkwood, the Vale of Anduin has a strong starting location.\n\nEarly Game:\nThe above appraisal comes with a major drawback, the Valesmen are bordered on their southwestern side by the goblin tribes of Moria. These goblins conduct constant raids against the Vale and come with strength. Sadly, the situation does not get better to the southeast where the forces of Dol Guldur muster nor to the northwest where a new threat rises from the old mountain of Gundabad. The Valesmen's only glimmer of hope comes in the form of the Woodland Realm to their northeast, who start as a neutral party but a potential ally. All of the Valesmen's early attention should be turned to Moria and Dol Guldur because if their attention is turned elsewhere, they run the risk of being overrun very early.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nThough lacking heavy armour the men of the Vale are capable fighters and no strangers to skirmish with orcs from the Misty Mountains to the west and Mirkwood to the east. The mighty Beornings, secretive Woodmen and the few remaining descendants of Rhovanion combined field a highly versatile force. \n\nSpecial Features:\n- Skin-changers that turn into bears\n- Ambush Specialists\n- Keep the roads safe\n- Clear Mirkwood\n\nRare Units:\n- Silvan Marchwardens (Dol Guldur)\n- Skin-Changers\n- Carrock Guard
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_TITLE}Angmar
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_DESCR}Leader: Overlord Agandaûr\nHeir: Lord Scyld\nCapital: Carn Dûm\n\n\n\n"The Black Rider flung back his hood, and behold! he had a kingly crown; and yet upon no head visible was it set. The red fires shone between it and the mantled shoulders vast and dark. From a mouth unseen there came a deadly laughter. "Old fool!" he said. "Old fool! This is my hour. Do you not know Death when you see it? Die now and curse in vain!" And with that he lifted high his sword and flames ran down the blade." - Witch-king of Angmar\n\nStarting Location:\nThe Remnants of Old Angmar begin with only a handful of settlements to their name in the far cold north. They have alliances with the High Chief of Moria, Dol Goldur and the Dark Lord Sauron.\n\nEarly Game:\nBetween the lands of Angmar and the historic lands of Arthedain lie many independent villages, towns and castles: ruins of the once great cities that stood in Eriador. All are ripe for plundering.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nThe Angmarim have long preferred to meet their foe on foot in stout armour and that tradition endures. They have keen archers who have adapted to fighting the superior Dúnedain Rangers well. They hold an uneasy alliance with the Orcs of Mount Gram and the latter provide many mounted battalions: vicious Wargs with battle-ready Orc riders. Further afield, the ancient curse laid by the Witch-king on the burial mounds of the Dúnedain still bear forth undead monstrosities to this day that will still fight for the Iron Crown.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- The Witch-king of Angmar\n- Extra generals for capturing important settlements\n\nRare Units:\n- Barrow-wights\n- Snow-trolls\n- Darkblades\n- Northguard\n- Guardians of Carn Dûm
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORMANS_TITLE}Bree-land
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORMANS_DESCR}Leader: Custom Character \nHeir: First-Captain Aedilbert\nCapital: Bree\n\n\n\nSome will tell you that Bree is old.\n\nOlder than the Shire. Older than Minas Tirith. Older than Fornost. Older than the Havens. They tell that there has been a settlement here, on the Road, since the First Age of the World. And the Road passing through the Bree-land is ancient, for it was made by the Firstborn, long, long ago, when they passed this way heading West.\n\nFor others Bree is younger, as they say that the Men of Bree are cousins to the Dunlendings, a folk of Men that long ago dwelt in distant dales in the far south and that eventually moved north, to live in the foothills of the Misty Mountains.\n\nOf course, if you ask a Bree-lander most of the above is just pointless chatter. Bree-hill has always been there, and if you want to know about history, you will be regaled with an infinitely detailed recounting of village gossip, marriages, births, deaths, things said in the taproom of The Pony, things not said when they should have been said, and so forth. - Bree-land background\n\nStarting Location:\nNestled in the heartlands of Eriador, Bree starts in a very well protected position. Natural defences dot the landscape, such as hills, rivers and woodland. As far as control goes, the Breelanders start with a reasonable amount of regions however, most of their holdings are minor villages in the Shire.\n\nEarly Game:\nBree does not have very many neighbours at all and only one ally: the Dúnedain. Not far from the Shire's western border lie the Grey Havens and they have favourable relations with the Elves there, but there are no enemies to speak of as their nearest threat comes from Carn Dûm, way to the north. There are a lot of rebel provinces surrounding the Bree lands giving ample opportunity to expand in almost any direction.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nBree do not have a formal military and they have very few units compared to most nations. The Council of Bree has sent out a call to any able man, dwarf or elf to assist in it's defense. Who will take up this call and lead Bree's armies into battle is up to you. Your choice of character will determine your starting faction leader, their traits, ancilliaries, bodyguard and their starting army. Overall, the Bree-land's military consists of holding units over attacking units and favouring infantry over cavalry.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Rebuild the Forsaken Inn\n- Create a Custom Faction Leader\n- Unconventional Recruitment\n- Scouring of the Shire event\n- Isolation or Dúnedain Choice\n\nRare Units:\n- Gate Keepers
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_TITLE}Dale
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_DESCR}Leader: King Brand\nHeir: Prince Bard II\nCapital: Dale\n\n\n\n"But there was still a company of archers that held their ground among the burning houses. Their captain was Bard, grim-voiced and grim-faced, whose friends ... knew his worth and courage. He was a descendant in long line of Girion, Lord of Dale, whose wife and child had escaped down the Running River from the ruin long ago. ... Bard took the lead [after the attack on Laketown], and ordered things as he wished, ... he had a hard task to govern the people and direct the preparations for their protection and housing. Probably most of them would have perished in the winter ... But help came swiftly; for Bard at once had speedy messengers sent up the river to the Forest to ask the aid of the King of the Elves of the Wood..." - Wisdom of Bard and fortunes of Dale \n\nStarting Location:\nThe holdings of the Dalesmen stretch from the city of Dale out to the sparsely populated region of Erland’s Ferry and this gives them plenty of warning if an army is encroaching on their capital.\n\nEarly Game:\nTo the north, the Dwarves of the Iron Hills will be actively trying to create a buffer between the mountains and the sea of Rhûn. This land race will dominate Dale’s starting game. Once lines have been drawn, you can cross the River Running and lay claim to the lands of Rhovanion before Dorwinion or Dol Guldur do. Be wary of meeting Rhûn unprepared for they will outmatch you for many years.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nDale have a mixed military makeup but they focus mostly on ranged warfare. They have plenty of willing woodsmen and peasants who are eager to fight for Dale and can be used to engage the enemy whilst your superior archers finish them off. Additionally, Dale have one or two outstanding units that can turn battles in their favour and they have a nice variety of cavalry to help close the distance in the vast plains of the northeast.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Black Arrows (Armour Piercing)\n- Treasure recovery\n\nRare Units:\n- Athala Rangers (Rhovanion & Rhûn)\n- Elven & Dwarven Support (Dale)\n- Hearthguard\n- Aihwothiuda Horseguards\n- Barding Hird\n- Ships
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_TITLE}Dol Amroth
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_DESCR}Leader: Prince Adrahil\nHeir: Lord Imrahil\nCapital: Dol Amroth\n\n\n\n"[With Gandalf] went the Prince of Dol Amroth in his shining mail. For he and his knights still held themselves like lords in whom the race of Númenor ran true. Men that saw them whispered saying: 'Be like the old tales speak well; there is Elvish blood in the veins of that folk, for the people of Nimrodel dwelt in that land once long ago.'.... And last and proudest, [came] Imrahil, Prince of Dol Amroth, kinsman of the Lord, with gilded banners bearing his token of the Ship and the Silver Swan, and a company of knights in full harness riding grey horses; and behind them seven hundreds of men at arms, tall as lords, grey-eyed, dark-haired, singing as they came.... 'From helm to sea they saw him leap, As arrow from the string, And dive into the water deep, As mew upon the wing. The wind was in his flowing hair, The foam about him shone; Afar they saw him strong and fair Go riding like a swan'." - Tale of Amroth and Nimrodel and Nature of Dol Amroth\n\nStarting Location:\nDol Amroth is located on the western edge of the Belfalas peninsula. The city itself is surrounded on all sides by impassable cliffs and only the port of Dol Amroth acts as a suitable landing point. Belfalas itself is divided in two by a large mountain range stretching from the sea to the White Mountains. This gives Dol Amroth ample warning of any would be land invaders but also impedes their own armies marching north or south.\n\nEarly Game:\nWhilst Dol Amroth is a vassal and protectorate of the mighty nation of Gondor, in truth, they must rely on their own armies for protection. Gondor acts as a great bulwark against Mordor but in the south, new nations are taking shape that now threaten the Lands of the Prince. Before all out war is joined, it would be prudent to claim the independent lands of Harondor for the Swan so there is a buffer between the south and your heartlands.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nDol Amroth has one of the most highly trained military line ups of any faction: they have capable militia, excellent heavy infantry and the finest heavy cavalry in all of Middle-earth. Unfortunately, this excellence cannot be taught in only a few years and Dol Amroth has difficulty fielding large armies.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Fornost & Osgiliath Rebuilding\n\nRare Units:\n- Knights of the Silver Swan (Dol Amroth Heartlands)\n- Knights of Edhellond\n- Ships
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_TITLE}Dol Guldur
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_DESCR}Leader: Lord Khamûl\nHeir: Chieftain Lagoren\nCapital: Dol Guldur\n\n\n\n"There lies the fastness of Southern Mirkwood,' said Haldir. 'It is clad in a forest of dark fir, where the trees strive one against another and their branches rot and wither. In the midst upon a stony height stands Dol Guldur, where long the hidden Enemy had his dwelling. We fear that now it is inhabited again, and with power sevenfold. A black cloud lies often over it of late." - Power of Dol Guldur\n\nStarting Location:\nThe southern reaches of Mirkwood are a dark and gloomy place and it is from this gloom that the castle of Dol Guldur rises. Standing as a solitary peak above the labyrinthine forest below; the castle is Khamûl's sole holding.\n\nEarly Game:\nThe lands around the hill of Dol Guldur are mostly independent and it should not take long for them to be brought into the fold. Be cautious however for the men of the Vale and the Elves of the Wood will not give you much time before they attack. In fighting against them, you will mostly stand alone. Your nearest ally is Mordor and they will not provide aid.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nWith Dol Guldur isolated in the forest, their armies have shunned the horde like tactics of Sauron and instead focus on guerilla war. In addition, from the twisted mind of Khamûl they have managed to instil a poison in their arrow tips that will weaken any foe they hit; giving them an opportunity to end battles quickly or strike and flee. Should a battle be forced then they turn to Khamûl's countrymen to give them an edge against their foes.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Poison Arrows\n- Spiders\n- Ambush Specialists\n- Easterling Elites\n\nRare Units:\n- Khamûl’s Shadow Guard\n- Goblin Headhunters\n- Khamûl’s Shadow Rangers\n- Castellans of Dol Guldur\n- Spiders\n- Trolls
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_TITLE}Dorwinion
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_DESCR}Leader: Vinter-Regent Hawin\nHeir: First Councillor Swain\nCapital: Helcârin\n\n\n\n"the heady vintage of the great gardens of Dorwinion... a land of vines in 'the burning South.'" - Little known information on Dorwinion\n\nStarting Location:\nDorwinion is located in the eastern reaches of Rhovanion, bordered by the mountains and sea of Rhûn. Both of these natural features provide Dorwinion some protection from their Easterling neighbours. They begin with their capital; The Garden City (Helcârin), the castle of the Leofthiuda (Círdaleof) and the City of the Coastal Folk (Mithrin).\n\nEarly Game:\nThere are plenty of independent towns and castles in the wide grasslands of Rhovanion and Logathavuld that Dorwinion can easily claim before they need resort to all out war. The Darïtaï of Rhûn, being Dorwinion's nearest neighbour, start on neutral terms with the lands of wine and may not bring conflict in the early game. Beyond the Easterlings, the men of Dale and the Dwarves of Erebor hold as potential steadfast allies in the north.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nDorwinion have a unique military that depends upon the choices their ruling council and Vintner-Regent take, predominantly though they are a medium-armoured infantry faction, with good ranged units and lots of variety. They have some solid cavalry and if accord can be found with the Avari, they have some formidable elite troops.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Avari\n- Dragon Cult\n- Kantor buildings\n- Mordor proposal\n- Regentsmen Reforms\n\nRare Units:\n- Rouadengi Vintner-Court Nobles\n- Avarin Héruvi\n- Regents Grapevine-Lancers\n- Kugathi Rátha
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AZTECS_TITLE}Dunland
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AZTECS_DESCR}Leader: Gurach Kjaraz\nHeir: Huntmaster Merufingir\nCapital: Byrig\n\n\n\n"[The] Dunlendings seeing their chance came over the Isen and down from Isengard. It was soon known that Wulf was their leader. They were in great force, for they were joined by enemies of Gondor.... The Rohirrim were defeated and their land was overrun; and those who were not slain or enslaved fled to the dales of the mountains. Helm was driven back with great loss from the Crossings of Isen...." - Once great power of Dunland\n\nStarting Location:\nDunland lies in an area stepped in natural protection; Misty Mountains to the east, Greyflood to the west, Gap of Rohan to the south-east and the Glanduin River to the north. The Dunlendings however only have a few regions to their name.\n\nEarly Game:\nIsengard are Dunland's only ally and their closest neighbour. Rohan are the clansmen's nearest enemy and they begin at war. To the west of Dun Larach lie the holdings of the 'Clans of Enedwaith', a curious faction whose intentions remain unclear. North of the Gwathló River is where Dunland will find freely available land starting with the ruins of Tharbad, beyond that, war must be kindled with someone for Dunland to expand.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nDunland's military is predominantly comprised of highly damaging but lightly armoured clansmen. They focus on close range combat with limited ranged and cavalry options.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Isengard influence\n- Sub-races with custom bodyguards\n- Raiding\n- Sacrificial Omens\n- Reforms\n\nRare Units:\n- Wulfingir\n- Isendraich Towersworn\n- Frekkalingir\n- Skreulingir
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TEUTONIC_ORDER_TITLE}Enedwaith
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TEUTONIC_ORDER_DESCR}Leader: Mootlord Tremac\nHeir: Chieftain Harec\nCapital: Alcfud\n\n\n\n"A fairly numerous but barbarous fisher-folk dwelt between the mouths of the Gwathló and the Angren... tribes of 'Wild Men', fishers and fowlers, on the coasts of Enedwaith, who were akin in race and speech to Drúedain of Anórien." - Little known background of the clans\n\nStarting Location:\nEnedwaith is bounded to the north by the Gwathló river; to the west by the ocean; to the south by the White Mountains and; to the east by the Misty Mountains. This does give the clans various choke points to hold enemies out of their heartlands.\n\nEarly Game:\nThe clans are a totally independent nation and you have total freedom to choose who your enemies will be. Dunland starts on your eastern border with Isengard only a little further beyond them. South lies the great realm of Gondor and they will not be expecting an attack from the ‘rabble’ in Enedwaith. Crossing the Gwathló will bring you into contact with both Bree and the High Elves in Lindon and whilst the former may prove easy pickings, the latter will be a challenge to defeat. There are many rebel regions in the old lands of Cardolan and Minhiriath so you will have time to expand before you must declare war.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nThe clans rely heavily on ambush and guerrilla warfare: being neither the most numerous nor the strongest of people in Middle-earth. Their poor technological state and dis-unified nation leaves them outmatched by almost all other forces and even your relative elites will struggle to fight against Gondor’s early offerings. The free folk of Enedwaith do have one strength: their javelins. No other nation fields such deadly javelin throwers and even the walking immortals known as Eregion Smiths will fall like flowers before the hail of Enedwaith javelins.\n\nSpecial features:\n- Ambush Specialists\n\nRare Units:\n- Guardians of Enedwaith (United Enedwaith)\n- War Maidens\n- Foresters of Haleth\n- War Wagons\n- Ships
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_TITLE}Erebor
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_DESCR}Leader: King Dáin II Ironfoot\nHeir: Lord Thorin\nCapital: Erebor\n\n\n\n"Under the Mountain dark and tall, The King has come unto his hall! His foe is dead, the Worm of Dread, And ever so his foes shall fall! The sword is sharp, the spear is long, The arrow swift, the Gate is strong. The heart is bold that looks on gold; The dwarves no more shall suffer wrong... Now call we over the mountains cold, Come back unto the caverns old! Here at the gates the king awaits, His hands are rich with gems and gold. The king has come unto his hall Under the Mountain dark and tall. The Worm of Dread is slain and dead, And ever so our foes shall fall!" - Dwarven song\n\nStarting Location:\nThe Dwarves begin the game with only two mansions under their control: the great (now rebuilt) city of Erebor and their long standing home of Kirikhgathol in the Iron Hills.\n\nEarly Game:\nTo the south of the Iron Hills lies the vast land of Logathavuld. This unending sea of grassland is divided into many independent realms all vying for ultimate control. These lands would fall to the might of the Dwarves easily. Care must be taken however because the Kingdom of Dale, a close ally, and the Darïtaï of Rhûn, a bitter enemy, are also trying to occupy Logathavuld for their own military goals.\n\nIn addition to heading south, to the west the great mansion of Dain's Halls lies empty. We should seek to claim it for the glory of the Dwarves! However, with the rise of King Mazog, the filth of Gundabad may seek to defile the great hall if they should beat us to it.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nThe chief lesson that the Dwarves of Erebor have taken from the desolation of Smaug is that the best defence is a good offence. This ethos has been drilled into the armies of Erebor and, through rigorous training, they are now one of the most lethal fighting forces. Favouring manoeuvrability over defence, they have the deadliest of all dwarven charges and their skill with their weapons is unmatched. Further still, the army of Erebor fields no archers or crossbows and instead favours the lethal dwarven throwing axe. Allies from the Orocarni do still fight at range and a wise commander adopts both Erebor's offensive stance with support from the more defensive Orocarni.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Dwarven Grudges\n- Orocarni Hall\n- No Cavalry\n- No Mainstream Archers\n\nRare Units:\n- Hammers of Gundabad (Gundabad)\n- Sons of the Fallen (Misty Mountains)\n- Iron Guard\n- Axeguard of Erebor\n- Dragonslayers
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_TITLE}Ered Luin
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_DESCR}Leader: Clanlord Gor\nHeir: Clanherald Grain\nCapital: Thorin's Halls\n\n\n\n"But a small dark figure that none had observed sprang out of the shadows and gave a hoarse shout: Baruk Khazâd! Khazâd ai-mênu! An axe swung and swept back. Two Orcs fell headless. The rest fled." - Dwarven battle cry\n\nStarting Location:\nEred Luin have a simple start with 3 regions under firm Dwarvish control. In terms of natural protection, the Blue Mountains provide just that. Additionally the sheer remoteness of their homeland offers great protection.\n\nEarly Game:\nLindon start adjacent to Ered Luin's capital and have favourable relations with the Dwarves but don't start as allies. The Dwarves hold alliances with only the other dwarven nations for now. They also start close to the Breeland but their nearest threat is a long way away in the lands of Angmar. Before war is declared however, most of the lands of far Arthedain and Forochel are free for the taking. There are also some rebel villages dotting the foothills of Ered Luin that can be should be claimed quickly before the Elves decide they will stay and fight.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nWar has not been seen in the Blue Mountains since the world was founded and very few dwarves there have ever seen battle. Accordingly, the warriors of the Blue Mountains are not as skilled or bloodthirsty as their Iron Hills cousins. They are however excellent creators and through centuries of tinkering and practice they have perfected the crossbow. As a point of pride, and despite the lack of threats, they have always ensured that all dwarves train and use their mighty crossbows. So, whilst their melee forces may fall behind the other dwarven nations, their ranged divisions will always be a forced to be reckoned with.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Dwarven Rings Choice\n- Dwarven Relics\n\nRare Units:\n- Hammers of Gundabad (Mount Gundabad)\n- Grimborn Reavers\n- Azaghâl's Tomb Protectors
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HRE_TITLE}Goblins
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HRE_DESCR}Leader: High Chieftain Uglag\nHeir: Chieftain Agôrôlg\nCapital: Moria\n\n\n\n"Clap! Snap! the black crack! Grip, grab! Pinch, nab! And down, down to Goblin-town You go, my lad! Clash, crash! Crush, smash! Hammer and tongs! Knocker and gongs! Pound, pound, far underground! Ho, ho! my lad! Swish, smack! Whip crack! Batter and beat! Yammer and bleat! Work, work! Nor dare to shirk, While Goblins quaff, and Goblins laugh, Round and round far underground Below, my lad!" - Goblin prisoner song \n\nStarting Location:\nThe Misty Mountains are no longer unified as they were in the days of Azog and Bolg. Gundabad is now held by long forgotten kin who masquerade as ‘Melkor’s Chosen’. The foolish King of Goblin-town thinks himself above all goblins and has declared independence. As such, the goblins only hold Moria and Kala Gorge and stand alone.\n\nEarly Game:\nThe central location in Middle-earth gives the goblins plenty of early opportunities. You can head down into Eregion and reclaim the long abandoned towns there or march north and bring Goblin-town to heel. In any event, it will not be long before one of your many enemies starts making trouble. The Northern Dúnedain start but a few regions away and heavily outmatch us. The Valesmen have been fighting against the goblins for centuries and are strong foes. Lothlórien is with reach but only the foolish dare venture there!\n\nMilitary Overview:\nGoblins are the quintessential horde nation. Your forces are the weakest in Middle-earth but they are the most numerous. You will not defeat your foe through clever strategy or strength of arms but through sheer overwhelming numbers. The goblins are not wholly devoted to the horde however and have developed excellent crossbows and deadly war machines.\n\nThe Balrog will not fight for the goblins and does not feature in the campaign for them.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Khazad-dûm Expedition\n- Limited Cavalry and Elites\n\nRare Units:\n- Mountain Uruks (Mountain Regions)\n- Cave Trolls\n- Azog's Defilers\n- Drummers of the Deep
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_TITLE}Gondor
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_DESCR}Leader: Steward Denethor II\nHeir: Captain-General Boromir\nCapital: Minas Tirith\n\n\n\n"Believe not that in the land of Gondor the blood of Númenor is spent, nor all its pride and dignity forgotten. By our valour the wild folk of the East are still restrained, and the terror of Morgul kept at bay; and thus alone are peace and freedom maintained in the lands behind us, bulwark of the West. But if the passages of the River should be won, what then?" - Gondor's strength and problem \n\nStarting Location:\nGondor has many natural defences against her enemies: the Anduin protects from the hordes of Mordor, Khand and Harad and; the Ered Nimrais gives cover from the nations of Enedwaith. She is also the largest nation in Middle-earth and the potential of her economic strength is certainly comforting.\n\nEarly Game:\nMordor dominates Gondor's entire campaign and the opening days of the War of the Ring are no different. There are few independent holds in these embattled lands and Mordor will arrive at the ruins of Osgiliath within a few years. Gondor must mobilise her enormous strength quickly and strike fast before Sauron can bring Harad, Khand and his own hordes to full production. All hope is not lost however for Prince Adrahil commands many battalions of elite warriors from Dol Amroth and he has been tasked with holding the Mouths of the Anduin.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nGondor is a nation of heavy infantry and skilled armourers, and even its lowest tier warriors boast well-made armour and arms. The famous White Tree is emblazoned on fine plate mail and the sight of a fully equipped Gondorian army arrayed on the field will give pause to any would-be foe. The cavalry of Gondor is few and far between however and is not the favoured method of combat for the Númenórean descendants.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Fiefdom Recruitment\n- Fornost & Osgiliath Rebuilding\n- Beacons of Gondor\n- Denethor's madness\n- Berethor\n- Control Dol Amroth\n- Erech (Minor Settlement)\n\nRare Units:\n- Minas Ithil Guardians (Minas Morgul)\n- Fountain Guard\n- Knights of Anorien\n- Trebuchet (All Regions)\n- Ships
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GUNDABAD_TITLE}Gundabad
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GUNDABAD_DESCR}Leader: King Mazog\nHeir: Marauder-Chief Ghurzog\nCapital: Mount Gundabad\n\n\n\n"In the Dwarvish traditions of the Third Age the names of the places where each of the Seven Ancestors had 'awakened' were remembered ... that of the ancestor of the Longbeards [Durin's Folk] ... had been Mount Gundabad (in origin a Khuzdul name), which was therefore revered by the Dwarves, and its occupation in the Third Age by the Orcs of Sauron was one of the chief reasons for their great hatred of the Orcs. ... Though these [places of awakening] were far sundered the Dwarves of different kindreds were in communication, and in the early ages often held assemblies of delegates at Mount Gundabad." - Description of Mount Gundabad \n\nStarting Location:\nThe paths to Mount Gundabad are few and dangerous. Only from the Vale can an enemy come upon the mountain with ease. This offers excellent protection to the isolated start of the Snow-orcs.\n\nEarly Game:\nThe long abandoned Dwarven castle of Burzakûl should be the first stop on the campaign for domination. There are however no other independent garrisons in the frozen north and inevitably, war with Erebor will come.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nThe Orcs of Gundabad are strong, uncharacteristically so for orcs. The harsh conditions of the frozen tundra have shaped them into fierce warriors. They do not have the knowledge of armour as Isengard or Minas Morgul but they are certainly the finest of Melkor’s sons. They are also the least numerous however and their armies are not great in number. Snow-orcs are also keen sighted archers and are able to go toe-to-toe with human marksmen.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Orc Subjugation\n- Scavenged Dwarven Armour\n\nRare Units:\n- Orc Avengers (Dwarven Mansions)\n- Snow Trolls\n- Half-Trolls\n- Bolg's Champions\n- Pale Uruks
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_TITLE}Harad
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_DESCR}Leader: Serpent-Lord Khûzaymáh\nHeir: Warlord Mûsab\nCapital: Faen'obel\n\n\n\n"The Haradrim, a great and cruel people that dwelt in the wide lands south of Mordor beyond the mouths of Anduin.... a grim folk, and not easily daunted by shade or blade. Out of Far Harad black men like half-trolls with white eyes and red tongues." - Little known information on Harad\n\nStarting Location:\nThe 'Glittering City' of Faen'obel stands as the capital and only hold of the Black Serpent tribe. Khûzaymáh stands as sole inheritor of the Haradwaith has sworn his loyalty to Sauron. He has also brokered an alliance with the Variags of Khand and looks to secure the power of Harad in the greater region.\n\nEarly Game:\nExpansion prospects are in all directions for Harad: you can attempt to take the coast and cut off the King's Men or you can head north into Harondor and bring yourself to Gondor’s doorstep. Alternatively you can step back and consolidate in safety in Far Harad, allowing your rivals a chance to lock horns. Wherever you choose understand that you must expand in order to bring your more powerful allies to your cause.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nHarad have a mix of all unit types, they have swift cavalry and some solid infantry but they have no heavy infantry and very little in the way of anti-cavalry. Harad are also the herders of the most powerful unit in Middle-earth, the feared Oliphaunts!\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Unite the Tribes\n- Hasharii Assassins\n- Empire of the Haradwaith\n- Landmark Buildings\n\nRare Units:\n- Mûmakil\n- Troll-man Champions\n- Hasharii Shadows
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SAXONS_TITLE}High Elves
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SAXONS_DESCR}Leader: High Lord Elrond\nHeir: Lord Elladan\nCapital: Mithlond\n\n\n\n"In all the days of the Third Age, after the fall of Gil-galad, Master Elrond abode in Imladris, and he gathered there many Elves, and other folk of wisdom and power from among all the kindred of Middle-earth, and he preserved through many lives of Men the memory of all that had been fair; and the house of Elrond was a refuge for the weary and the oppressed, and a treasury of good counsel and wise lore." - Nature of Imladris \n\nStarting Location:\nThe hidden valley is one of the most well-protected corners of Middle-earth. With only two points of entry and one being across a river, it is nigh-on unassailable! It is however the only holding of the High Elves and whilst easily defended, you have no buffer zones to the enemy.\n\nEarly Game:\nThe Goblins of Moria are poised to assault Imladris at any moment from the southeast and the Angmarim are only a few provinces away to the north. There are numerous rebel settlements dotted around Rhudaur and the old lands of Hollin which are viable targets for Imladris however. There are also stout allies helping you in the early days such as the Northern Dúnedain, nestled safely in En Egladil. Even with various independent towns to seize, it will not be long before you have to assault Moria or face early obliteration.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nCenturies of brutal warfare against the shadow has made the remaining few Noldor the finest warriors on the face of Arda. Boasting Middle-earths’ best cavalry, infantry and archers, it is hard to see how any nation will hold back the High Elves. Unfortunately, the same conditions that have bred this excellent class of warrior have also caused the decline of their population and Imladris cannot field large armies at any time. \n\nSpecial Features:\n- House of the Mírdain\n- Elladan and Elrohir\n- Glorfindel’s Uncloaking\n- Galdor's Dream\n\nRare Units:\n- Mithlond Nobles\n- Gwaith-i-Mírdain\n- Eldarinwë Roquen
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_TITLE}Isengard
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_DESCR}Leader: Lord Saruman\nHeir: First Captain Lurtz\nCapital: Isengard\n\n\n\n"I think that I now understand what he is up to. He is plotting to become a Power. He has a mind of metal and wheels; and he does not care for growing things, except as far as they serve him for the moment. And now it is clear that he is a black traitor. He has taken up with foul folk, with the Orcs. ... Worse than that: he has been doing something to them; something dangerous. For these Isengard orcs are more like wicked Men. It is a mark of evil things that came in the Great Darkness that they cannot abide the Sun; but Saruman's Orcs can endure it, even if they hate it. I wonder what he has done? Are they Men he has ruined, or has he blended the races of Orcs and Men? That would be a black evil!" - Saruman's plans\n\nStarting Location:\nNan Curunir, The Wizard’s Vale, lies at the southernmost tip of the Misty Mountains and watches over the Fords of the Isen and the Gap of Rohan. From the great tower of the Orthanc, Saruman sees all that passes between east and west.\n\nEarly Game:\nRohan have not yet divined the treachery of Saruman and you will have a few years to prepare for all-out war with them. They are wary of the White Wizard but not yet warlike. Dunland bays for blood and will likely attack the lesser men of Enedwaith allowing you to focus wholly on the Horse lords. The towns between the Gap and the White Mountains are not currently beholden to any lord and are ripe for the taking in readiness for Rohan.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nSaruman, unlike Sauron, relies on quality over quantity and does not cheapen his armies with lesser orcs: relying mostly on the fighting Uruk-hai. These formidable warriors wear heavy armour to keep them protected against any threat and this keen understanding of armour is also displayed in the multitude of anti-armour units Saruman fields for war.\n\nSpecial Features:\n Saruman of Many Colours (One Ring Mechanic)\n- Limited Cavalry\n- Fangorn deforestation\n- Scouring of the Shire\n- Nazgûl (One Ring Mechanic)\n- Sharkû\n\nRare Units:\n- Nazg-hai (Ring Acquired)\n- Olog-hai (Mordor Regions)\n- Trolls\n- Guard of the Hand (Saruman’s Bodyguard)\n- Berserkers
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KHAND_TITLE}Khand 
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KHAND_DESCR}Leader: Khan Arkísh\nHeir: Warlord Órash\nCapital: Sturlurtsa Khand\n\n\n\n"Many of the Wainriders now passed south of Mordor and made alliance with men of Khand and of Near Harad; and in this great assault from north and south, Gondor came near to destruction." - Khand's history with Gondor and its neighbours\n\nStarting Location:\nThe Variags start nestled in the sleepy eastern regions of Middle-earth with a few small settlements. The gap of Khand provides a choke point to the north but to the south-west lies the vast wastes of Near Harad.\n\nEarly Game:\nTo the north is the nation of Rhûn; to the southwest lie the holdings of the Haradrim and; Mordor are to the west. The latter two start as allies of the Variags but Rhûn are neutral. Although not at war with anyone at the start, their nearest lore accurate enemies are Gondor to the far west and Dale to the North. The Variags have very little choice at the start of the game, there are a few rebel settlements to the immediate south but once those are claimed, they have to push through one of three allied lands to reach any battlefront. However, a cunning player can always bring the battle-lines closer with a well timed stab in the back of those closest...\n\nMilitary Overview:\nAs is to be expected of a Steppe nation, the Variags have excellent cavalry with a wide choice of units and the finest cavalry archers. Their excellence and reliance on cavalry leaves them wanting for foot infantry and foot archers however.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Blue Wizards\n\nRare Units:\n- Uushixià Stormriders & Orocarni Dwarves (Join Blue Wizards)\n- Great Beasts & Dark Númenóreans (Reject Blue Wizards)\n- Variag Veterans\n- Warlord's Kataphracts
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORWAY_TITLE}Khazad-dûm
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORWAY_DESCR}Leader: Highlord Balin\nHeir: Lord Oin\nCapital: Khazad-dûm East\n\n\n\n"The light of the shaft fell directly on a table in the middle of the room: a single oblong block, about two feet high, upon which was laid a great slab of white stone. ... On the slab runes were deeply graven.... BALIN SON OF FUNDIN, LORD OF MORIA.' The Company stood silent beside the tomb of Balin. Frodo thought of Bilbo and his long friendship with the dwarf, and of Balin's visit to the Shire long ago. In that dusty chamber [of Mazarbul] in the mountains it seemed a thousand years ago and on the other side of the world. 'I fear [the Book of Mazarbul] had ill tidings to record ...' said Gandalf. 'The first clear word is sorrow, but the rest of the line is lost, unless it ends in estre. Yes, it must be yestre followed by day being the tenth of November Balin lord of Moria fell in Dimrill Dale. He went alone to look in Mirror mere. an orc shot him from behind a stone. we slew the orc, but many more ... up from east up the Silverlode. ... Poor Balin! He seems to have kept the title that he took for less than five years.'" - True history of Balin's expedition \n\nStarting Location:\nKhazad-dûm East.\n\nEarly Game:\nRe-establish a foothold in Khazad-Dum and ensure it's survival.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nThe Expeditionary forces focus on the taking and holding of ground wherever possible. They craft mighty shields that they train with endlessly until the shield becomes an extension of their arm and they wear the finest dwarven armour in Middle-earth. This reliance on defence and armour does slow them down on the battlefield however. In order to not get completely bogged down, they field nimble archers to harass their enemies as the slow moving column of dwarven fury makes its way to the battle-lines!\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Explore and rebuild Khazad-dûm\n- Hail the seven Dwarven Clans\n- Explore the Vault of Uruktharbūn\n- No Cavalry\n- Highest Quality Armour\n\nRare Units:\n- Hammers of Gundabad (Mt Gundabad)\n- Hithaeglir Beast Hunters\n- First Legion
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_TITLE}King's Men
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_DESCR}Leader: Ar-Gimilkhâd\nHeir: Lord Gimilzôr\nCapital: None\n\n\n\n"The great cape and land-locked firth of Umbar had been Númenórean land since days of old; but it was a stronghold of the King's Men, who were afterwards called the Black Númenóreans, corrupted by Sauron, and who hated above all the followers of Elendil. After the fall of Sauron their race swiftly dwindled or became merged with the Men of Middle-earth, but they inherited without lessening their hatred of Gondor." - City of Umbar's past\n\nStarting Location:\nThe King's Men have come from the surviving Black Númenórean villages and towns far to the south of Middle-earth; they start with no provinces.\n\nEarly Game:\nFalling at the feet of Ar-Gimilkhâd is the decision of where to stretch the hand of the King's Men; the world is ready for colonisation and the early game will be what you make of it.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nIt is worth noting that the King's Men are a maritime nation and they can sail possibly the most able ships in Middle-earth, making naval power and exploration very easy. Their land strategy relies primarily on excellent heavy infantry supported by keen archers or crossbowmen. They field very limited cavalry; in the tradition of Númenor.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Auxiliary Recruitment (Most Humans)\n- Horde Nation\n- Fornost & Osgiliath Rebuilding\n- Pillar of Umbar\n\nRare Units:\n- Naru n'Aru Royal Knights\n- Ar-Pharazôn's Faithful\n- Alcarondas Sunderers
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_IRELAND_TITLE}Lothlórien
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_IRELAND_DESCR}Leader: Lord Celeborn\nHeir: High Marchwarden Haldir\nCapital: Caras Galadhon\n\n\n\n"It seemed to him that he had stepped through a high window that looked on a vanished world. A light was upon it for which his language had no name. All that he saw was shapely, but the shapes seemed at once clear cut, as if they had been first conceived and drawn at the uncovering of his eyes, and ancient as if they had endured for ever. He saw no colour but those he knew, gold and white and blue and green, but they were fresh and poignant, as if he had at that moment first perceived them and made for them names new and wonderful. In winter here no heart could mourn for summer or for spring. No blemish or sickness or deformity could be seen in anything that grew upon the earth. On the land of Lórien, there was no stain." - Power of Lórien \n\nStarting Location:\nLothlórien is a well-protected realm with rivers surrounding the capital of Caras Galadhon. These are the key defensive locations for the golden wood and must be held at all costs. Your second city is outside the borders of the forest to the south but is offered protection from its remoteness. n\nEarly Game:\nThe beginning of the campaign for Lórien will be dominated by the war with Dol Guldur. You can take the fight to the enemy and cut the head from the snake early or you can hold the Anduin against the poisonous shadow. In any event, you will have to deal with Dol Guldur early as there are few independent regions around the wood. Khazad-dûm hold the mountain pass to the west and war with them is difficult to begin and ill-advised.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nLothlórien are defensive experts. They have excellent archers and their melee forces can hold any line against almost any foe. With various heavily specialised units throughout their ranks they have an answer for any scenario.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Yavanna’s Union\n- Rumil and Orophin spawns\n\nRare Units:\n- Berio-i-Ngelaidh \n- Gûrveleg\n- Ents (Isengard)
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_TITLE}Mordor
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_DESCR}Leader: Sauron\nHeir: Witch-king\nCapital: Barad-dûr\n\n\n\n"Ash nazg durbatulûk, ash nazg gimbatul, Ash nazg thrakatulûk! agh burzum-ishi krimpatul." - Ring inscription\n\nStarting Location:\nThe realm of Mordor is, geographically, isolated. Mountains protect the heartlands on three sides and allies cover the gap to the east. This gives Mordor a very safe early game.\n\nEarly Game:\nThere are not many rebel regions for Mordor to expand into before they must face an enemy. Build up your infrastruce and economy. Applying pressure to Gondor as soon as possible is advised.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nMordor is a faction of many talents but they focus on cheap, poor-quality, orcs. With overwhelming numbers, your armies will pin down their enemy whilst the various elite units you have deal the killing blow. Your armies have poor morale, poor armour quality and poor weapon quality but vast numbers and powerful generals. The Nazgûl and their Dark Númenórean entourage will keep your hordes fighting long after the enemy has fled in fear.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Respawning Nazgûl\n- Sauron’s Return (One Ring Mechanic)\n\nRare Units:\n- Great Beasts (Mordor Regions)\n- Dark Númenóreans (Durthang)\n- Morgul Chosen\n- Olog-hai (Mordor Regions)\n- Great Beasts
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_TITLE}Northern Dúnedain
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_DESCR}Leader: Chieftain Aragorn\nHeir: Ranger-Captain Eldarion\nCapital: Fennas Drúnin\n\n\n\n"'Few now remember them,' Tom murmured, 'yet still some go wandering, sons of forgotten kings walking in loneliness, guarding from evil things folk that are heedless.' In those days no other Men had settled dwellings so far west, or within a hundred leagues of the Shire. But in the wild lands beyond Bree there were mysterious wanderers. The Bree-folk called them Rangers, and knew nothing of their origin. They were taller and darker than the Men of Bree and were believed to have strange powers of sight and hearing, and to understand the languages of beasts and birds." - Whispers of the Dúnedain Rangers\n\nStarting Location:\nThe Dúnedain have only two settlements to begin with and their armies are scattered across the old Arnor. Their capital is easily defensible with a forest blocking access and two rivers protecting its western, eastern and southern approach. Amon Sûl on the other hand has only a few hills for minor protection but is otherwise standing adrift amongst the plains.\n\nEarly Game:\nWhilst the Dúnedain start with few settlements, there are plenty of abandoned and independent towns in the lands of Cardolan, Arthedain and Rhudaur; including the great cities of Annúminas and Fornost. Once the independents are toppled though, war with Angmar is inevitable. The hatred they hold for the Dúnedain is fierce. Problems lie to the south and east as well as the Goblins of Moria have left their caverns to seek revenge on the surface world and the Dunlendings seek to expand their borders so as to better prepare for war with Rohan.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nThe Dúnedain have retained much of their ancient wisdom and their warriors are strong and powerful. With the finest human archers in Middle-earth for support, there are few enemies who can stand before a Dúnedain army. However, the long years and many wars have dwindled the Dúnedain population and their numbers are very few. Hope remains however on the shoulders of Aragorn son of Arathorn. Wherever he goes, humanity flocks to his banner: men of evil are turned back to the light and all will answer his call to arms for verily; is he not a Beacon of Hope for all the free peoples?\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Heartland Recruitment Restriction\n- Beacon of Hope (Mass Human Recruitment)\n- Fornost & Annúminas Rebuilding\n- Aragorn's journey\n- Gandalf\n- Arnor restoration\n- Reunited Kingdom\n\nRare Units:\n- Dúnedain Steelbowmen (Númenórean Cities)\n- Sons of Númenor (Annúminas)\n- Arthedain Knights\n- Arthedain Royal Guard\n- Tharbad Royal Guard
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_TITLE}Rhûn
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_DESCR}Leader: Lôke-khan Rhükar\nHeir: Khan Margöz\nCapital: Mistrand\n\n\n\n"The Easterlings were strong and war-hardened and asked for no quarter... In the meanwhile the Wainriders plotted their revenge. Beyond the reach of the arms of Gondor in lands east of the Sea of Rhûn from which no tidings came to its Kings, their kinsfolk spread and multiplied, and they were eager for conquests and booty and filled with hatred of Gondor which stood in their way. It was long, however, before they moved" - Easterlings hatred \n\nStarting Location:\nThe city of Mistrand is the jewel of the Sea of Rhûn and the Darïtaï have held sway here for thousands of years. Now the time has come to claim all of the east under the Golden Dragon!\n\nEarly Game:\nBefore they can claim Rhovanion in the name of Sauron, the Darïtaï must first conquer their neighbouring tribes. Every region in Rhûn swears fealty to a different lord and they must be brought to heel. Once the lands are united, the wine-drinkers of Dorwinion will no doubt seek to turn our victory to their financial gain but it is advised to crush them swiftly, before the Avari get wind of our plans!\n\nMilitary Overview:\nRhûn is a land of diversity and each tribe fights in a distinct style. Once brought together, the united Easterling army is one of few weaknesses: crossbows first shower the enemy with armour piercing bolts; keen sighted rangers then unleash dragon fire on the field; heavily armoured infantry then locks the enemy in place whilst lighter and more manoeuvrable battalions harass and flank and; finally, the Lôke-Innas Rim thunder across the plains to finish off any stragglers or hardened targets.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Dragon Fire Arrows\n- Unite the Clans\n- Dragon relics\n\nRare Units:\n- Süri'ut Chariots (Rhûn Regions)\n- Lôke-Innas Rim\n- Dragonswrath Units\n- Ships
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_TITLE}Rohan
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_DESCR}Leader: King Théoden\nHeir: Prince Théodred\nCapital: Edoras\n\n\n\n"Arise, arise, Riders of Théoden! Fell deeds awake: fire and slaughter! Spears shall be shaken, Shields shall be splintered, a sword-day, a red day, ere the sun rises! Ride now, ride now! Ride to Gondor! Death! Death! Death! Forth Eorlingas!" - Théoden's war cry\n\nStarting Location:\nRohan is located in the sleepy but soon to be war-torn region of south-west Rhovanion. They have a large collection of towns and castles under their control and are bordered on the south by the White Mountains; stretching across the entirety of their domain. The northern reach of their realm is marked by the Forests of Fangorn and Lothlórien.\n\nEarly Game:\nIn the populous regions of southern Rhovanion, there are few independent towns: only the Wold stands free of any liege lord. After these are brought into the fold, Rohan can attack west and take lands from Isengard or Dunland. Alternatively, there are opportunities to the northeast in the Brown Lands. War with your neighbours is inevitable but only Dunland is an active enemy at the outset. Gondor and Dol Amroth both hold as true allies beyond the White Mountains.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nRohan is a famed nation of horsemen and they boast the most diverse and numerous roster of cavalry in Middle-earth. Whilst they do also have a few dismounted units worthy of mention, for the most part, when their army isn't mounted it is made up of weak militia.\n\nSpecial Features:\n- Dwarves of the Glittering Caves\n- Gondorian reinforcements\n- Theoden's corruption\n\nRare Units:\n- Guards of Meduseld (Edoras)\n- Royal Guard\n- Guard of the Caves
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_TITLE}Woodland Realm
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_DESCR}Leader: King Thranduil\nHeir: Prince Legolas\nCapital: Thranduil's Halls\n\n\n\n"Now of old the name of that forest was Greenwood the Great, and its wide halls and aisles were the haunt of many beasts and of birds of bright song; and there was the realm of King Thranduil under the oak and the beech. But after many years, when well nigh a third of that age of the world had passed, a darkness crept slowly through the wood from the southward, and fear walked there in shadowy glades; fell beasts came hunting, and cruel and evil creatures laid there their snares. Then the name of the forest was changed and Mirkwood it was called, for the nightshade lay deep there, and few dared to pass through, save only in the north where Thranduil's people still held the evil at bay." - Fortunes of Mirkwood and strength of the Elves\n\nStarting Location:\nThe Woodland Realm begin with only two provinces in the far north of Mirkwood, they are boxed in to the north by the Ered Mithrin and to the east by the river Celduin. However to the west lie the flat plains of the Anduin Vale and south lies the vast forest of Mirkwood.\n\nEarly Game:\nAlmost entirely surrounded by allies or neutrals, the Woodland Realm start in a relatively strong position; Dale and Erebor to the east provide early allied support and the Anduin Vale to the west buffers them from the goblins of Moria. It will not be long however until the forces of Dol Guldur push up from the south, providing the woodland realms' main threat. Additionally, the Vale of Anduin cannot hold back the goblins or forces of Gundabad for long. A few choices are presented to the woodland realm at the start: they can push northwest and claim the rebel castle of Withibord or they can begin claiming the forest to the south at Emyn-nu-Fuin or Eryn Dholen. From there, their path lies either further west into the mountains via the Goblins holdings or the complete cleansing of Mirkwood down to Dol Guldur.\n\nMilitary Overview:\nThe Elves of Mirkwood rely heavily on archers and ranged units. They can get elite archers quicker than most races and have superior basic archers, that they can field in large numbers. They have average infantry however until their elite 'Arachîr' units can be trained that can hold their own against most units in the game. They are lacking in cavalry with only 2 options, both of which are designed to skirmish with the enemy not engage in prolonged melee.\n\nSpecial Features:\n\n- Eryn Lasgalen Creation\n\nRare Units:\n- Hin e-Daur\n- Ents (Isengard)\n- Aredhirith
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_UNITED_TITLE}Reunited Kingdom
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_UNITED_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_TITLE}The Dark Lord
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_DESCR}Useful for AI only campaigns\n\nSelect only this faction and enter the command 'control papal_states' or Press CTRL+SHIFT+A to relinquish control of the Papal States to the AI.
 