¬ Generated by localisation spreadsheet
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_INCOME}Settlement Income
{TMT_LOYALTY_TOOLTIP_REVOLTING}Loyalty: Potential for revolt
{TMT_LOYALTY_TOOLTIP_RIOTING}Loyalty: Potential for riots
{TMT_LOYALTY_TOOLTIP_DISILLUSIONED}Loyalty: Disillusioned
{TMT_LOYALTY_TOOLTIP_CONTENT}Loyalty: Content
{TMT_LOYALTY_TOOLTIP_HAPPY}Loyalty: Happy
{TMT_GROWTH_TOOLTIP_GROWTH}Population: Increasing
{TMT_GROWTH_TOOLTIP_STATIC}Population: No Growth
{TMT_GROWTH_TOOLTIP_DECLINING}Population: Decreasing
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_STATUS_TRAINING}Currently training units
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_STATUS_BUILDING}Currently constructing buildings
{TMT_LCLICK_FOR_BUILD_OPTIONS}Left-click to see upgrade options for this building
{TMT_CONSTRUCTION_HELP}Left-click to add to queue
{TMT_CONSTRUCTION_REMOVE_HELP}Left-click to remove from queue
{TMT_COST_OF_CONSTRUCTION}Cost to construct item
{TMT_TIME_TO_CONSTRUCT}Number of turns required to construct item
{TMT_COST_OF_RECRUITMENT_UNIT}Cost to recruit unit
{TMT_TIME_TO_RECRUIT}Number of turns required to train
{TMT_SEASON_SUMMER}Summer
{TMT_SEASON_WINTER}Winter
{TMT_REMAINING_ACTION_POINTS}Movement points\nThe dark blue bar represents points remaining\nLight blue section represents affect\non movement points after current\naction is performed
{TMT_ACCEPT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION}Build selected item
{TMT_CANCEL_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION}Do not build anything
{TMT_BUILD_FORT_OR_WATCHTOWER}Construct fort or watchtower
{TMT_CANNOT_BUILD_FORT_OR_WATCHTOWER}Cannot construct fort or watchtower here
{TMT_CANNOT_ATTACK_FROM_SIEGED_SETTLEMENT}When under siege it is only possible to attack the sieging army
{TMT_SHOW_GENERAL_UNIT_DETAILS}Show unit details for this character's bodyguard unit
{TMT_LCLICK_SELECT}Left-click to select
{TMT_RCLICK_INFO}Right-click to get further information
{TMT_LDBL_CLICK_INFO}Double Left-click to get further information
{TMT_CURSOR_ATTACK}Right-click to attack
{TMT_CURSOR_MOVE}Right-click to move to position
{TMT_CURSOR_SELECT}Right-click to select
{TMT_CURSOR_MOVE_MAP}Scroll map
{TMT_CURSOR_MOUSE_LOOK}Mouse look
{TMT_CURSOR_CLICK_DOWN}Click down
{TMT_CURSOR_EXCHANGE}Right-click to exchange units and characters 
{TMT_CURSOR_DEFAULT_ACTION}Right-click to perform mission
{TMT_CURSOR_NO_ACTION}No action possible on this target
{TMT_CURSOR_ENTER_SETTLEMENT}Right-click to enter settlement
{TMT_CURSOR_DISEMBARK}Right-click to disembark
{TMT_CURSOR_SET_RALLY_POINT}Right-click to set settlement's rally point
{TMT_CURSOR_AUTO_MERGE}Right-click to merge units 
{TMT_NO_MULTITURN_MISSIONS}Cannot attack or perform missions over multiple turns
{TMT_NO_MULTITURN_EXCHANGES}Cannot merge or exchange units over multiple turns
{TMT_SIEGE_EQUIPMENT_NOT_REQUIRED}Construction of this siege equipment is not required
{TMT_NO_DIPLOMACY_WITH_REBELS}Diplomacy is not possible with rebels
{TMT_TIMBER_TOOLTIP}Lumberyard: provides a minor trade resource.
{TMT_GRAIN_TOOLTIP}Grain Mill: provides a minor trade resource.
{TMT_COAL_TOOLTIP}Orchard: provides a minor trade resource.
{TMT_WOOL_TOOLTIP}Sheep Farm: provides a moderate trade resource.
{TMT_FISH_TOOLTIP}Fishery: provides a moderate trade resource.
{TMT_MARBLE_TOOLTIP}Apiary: provides a moderate trade resource.
{TMT_FURS_TOOLTIP}Trappers: provides a valuable trade resource.
{TMT_WINE_TOOLTIP}Vineyard: provides a valuable trade resource.
{TMT_AMBER_TOOLTIP}Village: provides valuable local trade bonus.
{TMT_TEXTILES_TOOLTIP}Textile Mill: provides a valuable trade resource.
{TMT_IRON_TOOLTIP}Iron: once upgraded, provides an excellent trade resource.
{TMT_IVORY_TOOLTIP}Labour Camp: provides an excellent trade resource.
{TMT_SILK_TOOLTIP}Silk Farm: provides an excellent trade resource.
{TMT_TOBACCO_TOOLTIP}Durin's Tower: an ancient tower of the Dwarves.
{TMT_SILVER_TOOLTIP}Silver: once upgraded, provides an excellent trade resource.
{TMT_GOLD_TOOLTIP}Gold: once upgraded, provides an excellent trade resource.
{TMT_CHOCOLATE_TOOLTIP}Mithril: an extremely rare and valuable trade resource.
{TMT_DOGS_TOOLTIP}Horse Corral: provides a valuable trade resource.
{TMT_CAMELS_TOOLTIP}The Carrock: a large stony river island in the upper reaches of the River Anduin.
{TMT_ELEPHANTS_TOOLTIP}Beacon of Gondor: part of the network of signal towers used to muster Gondor's fiefs and allies to war.
{TMT_SLAVES_TOOLTIP}Barrows: site of a group of ancient burial mounds.
{TMT_DYES_TOOLTIP}White Towers of Emyn Beraid: three tall elven towers which hold a Palantir.
{TMT_SUGAR_TOOLTIP}Hobbit Farmstead: provides an excellent local trade bonus.
{TMT_SULFUR_TOOLTIP}Pig Farm: provides a moderate trade resource
{TMT_TIN_TOOLTIP}The Gates of Argonath: giant statues of Isildur and Anárion.
{TMT_SPICES_TOOLTIP}Durin's Tower: an ancient tower of the Dwarves.
{TMT_COTTON_TOOLTIP}Rammas Echor: a great ancient wall surrounding Minas Tirith and enclosing the Pelennor Fields.
{TMT_ROADS_TOOLTIP}Road: Allows armies to march further\nAlso adds to trade income\nThe amount of traffic indicates the amount of trade
{TMT_PAVED_ROADS_TOOLTIP}Paved road: Allows armies to march efficiently at speed\nAlso adds to trade income\nThe amount of traffic indicates the amount of trade
{TMT_HIGHWAYS_TOOLTIP}Trade Route: Allows traders and armies to march long distances\nAlso adds to trade income\nThe amount of traffic indicates the amount of trade
{TMT_SEA_LANES_TOOLTIP}Trade route between settlements with ports
{TMT_FAMOUS_BATTLE_SITE_TOOLTIP}An epic battle of great renown was fought here
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_0}A ripe turnip has more influence over the ways of men than this lowly wretch
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_1}Even when he is full of conviction, nobody listens too much to this man
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_2}It is said even this man's wife barely takes heed of what he says
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_3}Though his statements are usually considered sound, he lacks the charisma to influence others
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_4}This man is considered decent counsel, but is yet to hold any real presence in the royal courts
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_5}Considered important enough that most minor lordlings would listen carefully to his counsel
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_6}Though he may not always win every debate he enters, his counsel always wins him respect
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_7}Is known to be able to make others adopt a perspective that is otherwise against their beliefs
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_8}Considered an even-handed font of wisdom on most matters, even by the enemies of his people
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_9}So convincing are this man's arguments that he can manipulate a learned audience with ease
{TMT_INFLUENCE_LEVEL_10}Scholars follow this man, seeking to quote his highly influential statements and musings
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_0}So naive and innocent is this one, he lacks the cunning to sneak up on even a corpse
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_1}Clumsy and conspicuous, only a fool would rely on this man for acts of espionage
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_2}He may be willing to do the dubious, but he lacks the guile and cunning to do it well
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_3}More cunning than most of the night watch... But not all of them
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_4}Usually capable of pulling off minor acts of espionage given the proper preparation
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_5}Discreet and delicate enough to be entrusted with dangerous clandestine tasks
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_6}Has proven more than capable of committing cunning clandestine acts
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_7}Foxes and weasels have nothing on this man in terms of raw cunning
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_8}Not even a bloodhound could track this man's movements, he is but a shadow
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_9}This man is the embodiment of subtlety, secrecy and stealth
{TMT_SUBTERFUGE_LEVEL_10}Like the shadows themselves, this man is everywhere at once without being tangible anywhere. 
{TMT_TOGGLE_AUTOMANAGEMENT}Toggle auto-management of this settlement
{TMT_DECREASE_TAXATION}Decrease taxation
{TMT_INCREASE_TAXATION}Increase taxation
{TMT_CHANGE_GOVERNOR_POLICY}Change governor policy
{TMT_DECREASE_GAMES_FREQUENCY}Decrease frequency of games and/or races
{TMT_INCREASE_GAMES_FREQUENCY}Increase frequency of games and/or races
{TMT_CURRENTLY_SELECTED_CHARACTER}Character currently selected:
{TMT_CURRENTLY_SELECTED_SETTLEMENT}Settlement currently selected:
{TMT_CURRENTLY_SELECTED_FORT}Fort currently selected
{TMT_CURRENTLY_SELECTED_RALLY_POINT}Rally point currently selected
{TMT_CURRENTLY_SELECTED_RALLY_POINTS}Rally points currently selected
{TMT_LCLICK_ZOOM_TO_POS}Left-click to locate item on map
{TMT_SHOW_SELECTED_ITEM}This area shows the currently selected item
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_NO_GENERAL}Armies without generals cannot construct forts or watchtowers
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_NOT_NAMED_CHARACTER}Only generals can commission forts and watchtowers
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_IN_SEA_REGION}Cannot build a fort or watchtower in the sea
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_FORT_IN_ENEMY_TERRITORY}Cannot build a fort in enemy territory
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_FORT_INVALID_GAME_TILE}This is an invalid position for a fort
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_FORT_NOT_ENOUGH_MONEY}You do not have enough money to build a fort
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_WATCHTOWER_IN_ENEMY_TERRITORY}Cannot build a watchtower in enemy territory
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_WATCHTOWER_INVALID_GAME_TILE}This is an invalid position for a watchtower
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_WATCHTOWER_NOT_ENOUGH_MONEY}You do not have enough money to build a watchtower
{TMT_NOT_ENOUGH_MONEY_FOR_FORT_OR_WATCHTOWER}You do not have enough money to build a fort or watchtower
{TMT_CANNOT_RECRUIT_UNITS_IN_BATTLE}You cannot recruit units or mercenaries once a battle has been instigated
{TMT_NO_BODYGUARD_UNIT_TO_VIEW}There is no bodyguard unit to view for this character
{TMT_NOT_ENOUGH_INFO_FOR_BODYGUARD}Not enough information gathered about this character to view his bodyguard unit
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_STATUS_AUTOMANAGED}This settlement is auto-managed
{TMT_PIGS_TOOLTIP}Pigs: Allows the training of incendiary pig units
{TMT_CANNOT_ATTACK_SIEGED_SETTLEMENT}Cannot lay siege to a settlement that is besieged by a non allied faction
{TMT_CANNOT_CONSTRUCT_WHILST_SIEGING}Cannot build forts or watchtowers whilst laying siege
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_WATCHTOWER_SIEGING}Cannot build a watchtower whilst laying siege
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_FORT_SIEGING}Cannot build a fort whilst laying siege
{TMT_NEGATIVE_COMMAND}This man actually manages to hinder any chance his subordinates have of achieving military success.
{TMT_NEGATIVE_INFLUENCE}When this man states an opinion, everyone knows that the opposite must be true.
{TMT_NEGATIVE_MANAGEMENT}This man can bring chaos out of order. He needs a 'to do' list when visiting a latrine, yet still manages to go horribly wrong!
{TMT_NEGATIVE_SUBTERFUGE}This man's bumbling naivety helps everyone he deals with become a master of cunning and subterfuge. 
{TMT_SLAVES_TOOLTIP_SINGLE}Slaves - a valuable resource\nDistributed across all settlements with governors. Resource is exhausted after 1 more turn
{TMT_SHOW_GENERAL_UNIT_DETAILS_ARMY}Show details of the bodyguard unit for this army's general
{TMT_LCLICK_INFO}Left-click to get further information
{TMT_CANNOT_MERGE_AGENT}The selected character cannot be received at this location
{TMT_CANNOT_MERGE_AGENTS}The selected characters cannot be received at this location
{TMT_AUTO_MERGE_AGENTS}Right-click to automatically merge agents
{TMT_GOLD_MINE_TOOLTIP}Gold Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_SILVER_MINE_TOOLTIP}Silver Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_IRON_MINE_TOOLTIP}Iron Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_MARBLE_MINE_TOOLTIP}Marble Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_SULFUR_MINE_TOOLTIP}Sulphur Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_TIN_MINE_TOOLTIP}Tin Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_AMBER_MINE_TOOLTIP}Amber Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_COAL_MINE_TOOLTIP}Coal Mine: A valuable source of income
{TMT_NO_WITHDRAW_NAVY}Cannot withdraw: Navies cannot withdraw from battles
{TMT_NO_WITHDRAW_AMBUSH}Cannot withdraw: You have been successfully ambushed
{TMT_NO_WITHDRAW_SIEGE}Cannot withdraw: Your are under siege
{TMT_NO_WITHDRAW_AP}Cannot withdraw: No movement points remaining
{TMT_NO_WITHDRAW_RETREAT}Cannot withdraw: Nowhere to withdraw to
{TMT_ALREADY_CAPITAL}This settlement is already the capital
{TMT_NO_GENERAL_UNIT_TO_SHOW}No personal bodyguard unit to show
{TMT_DOCK_BLOCKADED}This dock is currently blockaded
{TMT_PORT_BLOCKADED}This port is currently blockaded
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_AUTOMANAGED_BUILDING}Cannot add this building as construction is being auto-managed
{TMT_SETTLEMENT_AUTOMANAGED_TRAINING}Cannot add this unit as recruitment is being auto-managed
{TMT_CANNOT_RECRUIT_MERCS_IN_BATTLE}Cannot recruit mercenaries once a battle has been instigated
{TMT_CANNOT_CHANGE_TAX_LEVEL_AS_AUTOMANAGED}Cannot change the tax level of this settlement as the faction's taxes are being auto-managed. Go to the faction summary scroll to change this
{TMT_CANNOT_CHANGE_CASTLE_TAX_LEVEL}Cannot change the tax level of the castle.
{TMT_CANNOT_DESTROY_THIS_BUILDING}This building cannot be destroyed
{TMT_RECOUP_AMOUNT}%d gold coins will be recouped.
{TMT_CANNOT_LEAVE_ZOC}Cannot move through an enemy's zone of control
{TMT_CAN_ONLY_SALLY_OUT_ONCE_PER_TURN}Can only sally out once per turn
{TMT_CANNOT_FLEE}This army cannot flee from the battle. If it loses, all units will be destroyed
{TMT_LOYALTY_TITLE}Loyalty
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_0}It is doubtful if this man has any loyalties at all, even unto himself
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_1}This man perceives loyalty as a trait of the weak and foolish
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_2}He may proclaim his loyalty as expected, though it is quite obviously just for appearances
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_3}Fallible like any other man, at least this one tries to be a good servant
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_4}Understands that acting obediently is sometimes more important than doing what would seem sensible
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_5}Loyal enough to obey an order that he does not see the sense behind without complaint
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_6}This man would only disobey an order if he truly believed that he would be commended for it afterwards
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_7}Even upon threat of death, this man is willing to endure great hardships in service of his master and people
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_8}Unquestioningly loyal, this man is an asset that his people can always depend upon 
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_9}When this man's master commands him, he knows that it will be done, or he shall die trying
{TMT_LOYALTY_LEVEL_10}This man is spoken of far and wide as the epitome of selfless obedience, and is universally admired for it
{TMT_NEGATIVE_LOYALTY}This man actually revels in deceiving and betraying any whom he believes trust him
{TMT_HORDE_OCCUPY_SETTLEMENT_TOOLTIP}Take this settlement and the surrounding region as a new homeland for your people. Your hordes will disband.
{TMT_HORDE_SACK_SETTLEMENT_TOOLTIP}Steal everything you can from this settlement. Wreak havoc, and continue the search for a new homeland for your hordes.
{TMT_CANNOT_LEAD_NIGHT_BATTLE}The commanding officer in this battle cannot lead night attacks
{TMT_CANNOT_DISEMBARK_HERE}Cannot disembark here
{TMT_CANNOT_FLEE_HORDE_PLAYER}This army cannot flee from the battle. If it loses, the settlement will be lost and all your people will be forced to find another land to call home
{TMT_CANNOT_FLEE_HORDE_NON_PLAYER}This army cannot flee from the battle. If it loses, the settlement will be lost and this nations people will be forced to find another land to call home
{TMT_SIEGE_EQUIPMENT_NOT_POSSIBLE}Construction of this siege equipment is not possible
{TMT_MEET_ENEMY}Sally forth to meet the enemy outside settlement
{TMT_MEET_ENEMY_AUTORESOLVE}Automatically resolve the battle outside settlement
{TMT_REMAIN_GARRISON}Keep your garrison inside the settlement
{TMT_FLEE}Flee, abandoning the settlement to the enemy
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_0}There's little to separate this wretched creature from a bar wench
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_1}More of a spoiled brat than an example of nobility
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_2}Lacks the grace and charm of other ladies of the court
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_3}Delicate enough to win over a simpler sort of man easily enough
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_4}About as enthralling as one expects from a princess
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_5}One of the fairer ladies of the royal courts
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_6}Graceful and endearing enough to instil trust in others
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_7}Beautiful and capable, her majesty is a true asset to her people
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_8}Intoxicatingly charming enough to always get what she wants
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_9}So charming that most men would fight to see her will be done
{TMT_CHARM_LEVEL_10}Her majesty's grace and charm makes her a dangerous political weapon
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_0}This man may like money, but he is useless with it
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_1}Barely grasps the basics of the barter system
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_2}Boasts no more business acumen than a common market vendor
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_3}An aspiring trader, possessing more ambition than experience or ability
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_4}A competent yet uninventive warrior of the mercantile world
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_5}Boasts a sound knowledge of local and foreign markets
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_6}Knows how to use money to achieve goals that strength and honour cannot
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_7}Can lay siege to your enemies coffers with almost certain success
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_8}Silver-tongued enough to sell paintings to the blind
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_9}A master of making money multiply with little effort on a grand scale
{TMT_FINANCE_LEVEL_10}An infamous fiscal power in his own right
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_0}It helps that this man is illiterate because that way, he can't read the reports of how shockingly bad at governance he is.
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_1}The horse this man rode in on is frequently asked to make decisions in his stead.
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_2}With a keen grasp of single-syllable words and a command of counting up to 100, here is a governor in the making.
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_3}The people have stopped burning this man's belongings when he pops to the shops. 
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_4}Aided by some solid public speaking skills, this man has started to garner a grasp of rulership.
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_5}A competent ruler, neither hated nor loved: simply tolerated.
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_6}The townsfolk have been heard to use this man's name in sentences with the words 'success' and 'good job'.
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_7}The city square fills to bursting when this man takes to the stage, he is universally loved as a ruler. 
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_8}A small cult has gathered around this man and they are one tax cut away from outright worshipping the ground he walks on.
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_9}It is said that Finarfin often visits this man in dreams to ask for advice on city governance.
{TMT_PIETY_LEVEL_10}This man could turn the pits of Angband into the halls of Tirion inside of a week. He is one of the finest bureaucrats in Middle-earth. 
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_0}Infamous amongst the men because he lost a battle of wits to a one-legged chicken. 
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_1}In his last battle, he at least got the men to run in the right direction. 
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_2}Whilst eager, this man has yet to truly prove himself on the battlefield.
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_3}A few skirmish wins under his belt, and something of an 'up-and-comer'. 
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_4}A competent general, not beloved by the men but not hated either.
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_5}A lifesize statue has been erected in this man's hometown: they, at least, are proud of his military accomplishments.
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_6}A solid general with a keen grasp of the ways of war. 
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_7}This man has been lauded for his military skill for so long he is thinking of starting an academy.
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_8}A dependable and beloved general who commands with an iron fist.
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_9}A master strategist, soldiers from every corner of our realm wish to serve under him. 
{TMT_COMMAND_LEVEL_10}One of only a handful of generals who can liken themselves to great generals such as Eönwë and Gothmog.
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_0}It is said that this man's own mother sometimes forgets his name. 
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_1}This man was voted "least likely to succeed" at his academy graduation.
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_2}A malformed potato, bearing striking resemblance to Sauron, is better known than this man. 
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_3}He once thought somebody waved to him on the street: he was mistaken. 
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_4}The men no longer ask "who?" when told they are in this man's command. 
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_5}When this man passes through camp, he is met with reverential nods by his men. 
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_6}A widely popular book series has been released based upon this man's deeds. 
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_7}A small fan club now follows this man wherever he goes.
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_8}There is a widely held belief that those who fight under this man are invincible. 
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_9}There are now so many academies named after this man he has hired doppelgangers to attend the opening ceremonies. 
{TMT_CHIVALRY_LEVEL_10}Melkor himself has heard this man's name from the void. The men serve him with fervor!
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_0}No challenge
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_1}No challenge
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_2}Very easy
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_3}Easy
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_4}Medium
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_5}Medium
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_6}Hard
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_7}Hard
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_8}Very hard
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_9}Heroic
{TMT_MAGIC_LEVEL_10}Legendary
{TMT_NEGATIVE_CHARM}So vile is this woman that the doomsayers consider her a bad omen
{TMT_NEGATIVE_FINANCE}It is questionable whether or not this man can count properly
{TMT_NEGATIVE_PIETY}This man stops just short of creating his own realm
{TMT_NEGATIVE_MAGIC}Her only power is to inspire gossip and rumours amongst nervous villagers
{TMT_RESOURCE_TRADE_VALUE}Trade resource worth %d gold coins per turn
{TMT_TRADER_TRADE_VALUE}Trading %S, generating %d gold coins per turn
{TMT_TRADER_TRADE_TYPE}Trading %S
{TMT_NUM_MARRIAGES}%d marriage alliances with this faction 
{TMT_NEGATIVE_CHIVALRY}DO NOT TRANSLATE: SHOULD NEVER DISPLAY - negative chivalry
{TMT_NEGATIVE_DREAD}DO NOT TRANSLATE: SHOULD NEVER DISPLAY - negative dread
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_0}Neither remarkably respected nor nefarious
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_1}More concerned with survival than fighting honourably
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_2}Known for adopting less than admirable tactics to achieve victory
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_3}Has a habit of unnerving seasoned opponents with his overly grizzly ways
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_4}Consciously works terror and blackmail into his strategies
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_5}Some say his troops follow him out of fear rather than loyalty or pride
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_6}Shamelessly takes pleasure in causing pain and suffering
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_7}Commonly tortures his subjects as a display of authority
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_8}A leader so malevolent, he considers honour and virtue foolish weaknesses
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_9}A notorious champion of darkness capable of evils few others are
{TMT_DREAD_LEVEL_10}Even the dauntless must be forced to face such a leader
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_0}Even his own servants think twice before completing their chores
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_1}This leader has a serious inability to inspire others to follow
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_2}He simply lacks the spine and presence expected of a ruler
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_3}Some of his subjects will see things his way, yet not the majority
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_4}Though he has his detractors, he is too well respected for them to work openly
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_5}There is a general acceptance that his majesty is a competent ruler
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_6}Carries himself strongly enough to inspire confidence in his court
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_7}A natural born leader, rarely challenged or questioned
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_8}Capable of making men willingly follow a cause to their demise
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_9}Leads in a manner so inspiring none would think to question him
{TMT_AUTHORITY_LEVEL_10}His people consider his word nothing less than divine mandate
{TMT_NEGATIVE_AUTHORITY}Purely a figurehead, this man's people do not think of him as their leader
{TMT_JOIN_CRUSADE}Join the invasion
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_NOT_CALLED}There is no invasion in progress to join
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_CHARACTER_EXCOMMUNICATED}A character without Sauron's protection cannot join the invasion
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_TOO_LATE}It's too late to join the invasion
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_CHARACTER_IN_RESIDENCE}Cannot join the invasion whilst in a settlement or fort
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_CHARACTER_ON_FLEET}Cannot join the invasion whilst at sea
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_CHARACTER_NOT_ARMY_COMMANDER}Only the army commander may join the invasion
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_CRUSADE_INSUFFICIENT_UNITS}This character has too few units to join the invasion
{TMT_ABANDON_CRUSADE}Abandon invasion
{TMT_JOIN_JIHAD}Join the Tol Acharn
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_NOT_CALLED}There is no Tol Acharn in progress
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_TOO_LATE}It's too late to join the Tol Acharn
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_CHARACTER_IN_RESIDENCE}Cannot join the Tol Acharn whilst in a settlement or fort
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_CHARACTER_ON_FLEET}Cannot join the Tol Acharn whilst at sea
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_CHARACTER_NOT_ARMY_COMMANDER}Only the commanding general may join the Tol Acharn
{TMT_CANNOT_JOIN_JIHAD_INSUFFICIENT_UNITS}This character has too few units to join the Tol Acharn
{TMT_ABANDON_JIHAD}Abandon Tol Acharn
{TMT_CRUSADE_CANNOT_ATTACK_CATHOLIC}An invasion army cannot attack an evil faction
{TMT_JIHAD_CANNOT_ATTACK_MUSLIM}An army on a Tol Acharn cannot attack an Islamic faction
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE}Request the Dark Lord of Mordor to commission an invasion
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_IN_PROGRESS}Invasion already in progress	
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_NOT_ENOUGH_PAPAL_FAVOUR}Not enough favour points to request an invasion
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_TOO_SOON}Too soon since last invasion to request another
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_OK_NOT_SELECTED}Select an invasion target from the list first
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_OK_NO_TARGETS}No valid invasion targets available
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_OK}Request an invasion to the selected target
{TMT_CALL_CRUSADE_CANCEL}Close this scroll without requesting an invasion
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD}Declare a Tol Acharn
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_IN_PROGRESS}Tol Acharn already in progress
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_NOT_ENOUGH_RELIGION}This Imam lacks the Obedience required to call a Tol Acharn
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_TOO_SOON}Too soon since last Tol Acharn to call another
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_OK_NOT_SELECTED}Select a Tol Acharn target from the list first
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_OK_NO_TARGETS}No valid Tol Acharn targets available
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_OK}Call a Tol Acharn against the selected target
{TMT_CALL_JIHAD_CANCEL}Close this scroll without starting a Tol Acharn
{TMT_VOTE}Vote for this faction
{TMT_INITIATE_DIPLOMACY}Initiate diplomatic negotiations with this faction
{TMT_RESTRICTED_AREA}Restricted area 
{TMT_AVAILABLE_SUITORS}Potential suitors are in this army
{TMT_NO_AVAILABLE_SUITORS}No potential suitors in this army
{TMT_DIP_DEMEANOUR}A measure of how the other negotiator feels about you, and your proposals
{TMT_DIP_BALANCE}A measure of how generous or demanding your proposals are
{TMT_DIP_RELATIONS}A measure of how the other faction feels about yours
{TMT_DIP_REPUTATION}A measure of this faction's reliability
{TMT_DIP_POWER}A measure of this faction's military might
{TMT_DIP_WEALTH}A measure of this faction's current wealth
{TMT_DIP_PRIORITIES}Things this faction is believed to want from yours
{TMT_DIP_STANCES_NO_ALLIES}This faction has no allies
{TMT_DIP_STANCES_NO_ENEMIES}This faction is not at war with any other faction
{TMT_DIP_STANCES_ALLIES}Factions allied to this faction
{TMT_DIP_STANCES_ENEMIES}Factions at war with this faction
{TMT_DIP_STANCE_ALLIED}You are allied to this faction
{TMT_DIP_STANCE_NEUTRAL}You are neutral towards this faction
{TMT_DIP_STANCE_ENEMY}You are at war with this faction
{TMT_DIP_TRADE_RIGHTS_GRANTED}Number of turns trade rights have existed
{TMT_DIP_MILITARY_ACCESS_RECEIVED}Number of turns this faction has granted yours military access
{TMT_DIP_MILITARY_ACCESS_GIVEN}Number of turns you have granted this faction military access
{TMT_DIP_TRIBUTE_PAYED}Finances you are sending this faction each turn
{TMT_DIP_TRIBUTE_RECEIVED}Finances this faction is sending yours each turn
{TMT_DIP_ASSISTANCE_REQUESTED_AGAINST}The faction you have requested military assistance against
{TMT_DIP_ASSISTANCE_PROVIDED_AGAINST}The faction you have agreed to offer military assistance against
{TMT_DIP_PROTECTOR}The faction that this faction is offering you military assistance against
{TMT_NO_TREATIES}You have no diplomatic agreements at all with this faction
{TMT_RANSOM_BUTTON}Offer to ransom back the enemy troops
{TMT_RELEASE_BUTTON}Release the enemy troops
{TMT_EXECUTE_BUTTON}Execute the enemy troops
{TMT_ACCEPT_RANSOM_BUTTON}Agree to pay the ransom for your captured troops
{TMT_CANNOT_ACCEPT_RANSOM}Unfortunately, your coffers lack the funds required to pay the ransom
{TMT_REJECT_RANSOM_BUTTON}Decline to pay the ransom for your captured troops
{TMT_LCLICK_ZOOM_TO_CHARACTER}Left-click to locate character
{TMT_TIME_TO_NEXT_UNIT}Turns to next available unit: %d


{TMT_BUILD_WATCHTOWER}Construct watchtower
{TMT_CANNOT_BUILD_WATCHTOWER}Cannot construct watchtower here
{TMT_NOT_ENOUGH_MONEY_FOR_WATCHTOWER}You do not have enough money to build a watchtower
{TMT_FIELD_CONSTRUCTION_TEST_NOT_NAMED_CHARACTER_WATCHTOWER}Only generals can commission watchtowers

{TMT_HOTSEAT_MESSAGE}Click to send a hotseat message
{TMT_HS_CLEAR_BUTTON}Clear the current message
{TMT_HS_CANCEL_BUTTON}Cancel message to this player
{TMT_HS_SEND_BUTTON}Send message to this player
